<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-16T19:00:05-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Personal Blog of Sami Alperen Akgün</title><subtitle>Welcome to my personal blog! In this blog, I will try to share my experience and thoughts about academic life, travel, literature technology, music, movies and TV-series. You can use/share any information in here as long as you provide reference. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Mathpix Snip: Extract LaTeX from PDFs or handwritten notes in seconds just by taking a screenshot.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/16/mathpix.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mathpix Snip: Extract LaTeX from PDFs or handwritten notes in seconds just by taking a screenshot. " /><published>2020-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/16/mathpix</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/16/mathpix.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mathpix/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ubuntu Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although LaTeX and Overleaf makes your life easy when it comes to write a document and cite many papers, managing equations in LaTeX might be cumbersome sometimes. At least, that is the case for me nowadays. The problem about LaTeX and equations is even if you know all the syntax, you still need to waste a lot of time to type them into the document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I found the perfect tool to solve this problem, which is called &lt;strong&gt;Mathpix Snip&lt;/strong&gt;. This tool gives you to the ability to convert equations (either in pdf files or handwritten notes doesn’t matter) to LaTeX codes. It supports Mac, Windows and Linux. I tested on my Ubuntu 16.04 system and it worked like a charm. The program also has an app for both IOS and Android. According to the my experience, it doesn’t work 100% correct every time, but still I am impressed by its performance. Trust me, use this tool once and you are not going to regret it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can visit its official webpage using &lt;a href=&quot;https://mathpix.com/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. I didn’t take any money to advertise this tool :). I just feel sorry that I didn’t discover it before!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/mathpix/1.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/mathpix/1.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Use Ubuntu Properly: Workspaces, Shortcuts and Sliding Windows</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/11/ubuntu-compiz.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Use Ubuntu Properly: Workspaces, Shortcuts and Sliding Windows" /><published>2019-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/11/ubuntu-compiz</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/11/ubuntu-compiz.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ubuntu-compiz/ubuntu-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ubuntu Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I am going to explain my way of configuring Ubuntu to make my life easier. I hope it will be useful for you as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING:&lt;/strong&gt; I tested these methods on Ubuntu 16.04. Probably, they are going to be more or the less same for other versions, but there might be small differences!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, you should start using &lt;strong&gt;workspaces&lt;/strong&gt;. Workspaces refer to the grouping of windows on your desktop. You can create multiple workspaces, which act like virtual desktops. Workspaces are meant to reduce clutter and make the desktop easier to navigate. Workspaces can be used to organize your work. For example, you could have all your communication windows, such as e-mail and your chat program, on one workspace, and the work you are doing on a different workspace. Your music manager could be on a third workspace. Believe me workspaces are one of the great features of Linux!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enable workspaces:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Systems Setting-&amp;gt;Appearance&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;behavior&lt;/code&gt; tab.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tick &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;enable workspaces&lt;/code&gt; box.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ubuntu-compiz/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Enable workspaces&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, Ubuntu provides 2x2 workspaces. I personally, don’t like this. I prefer 3x1. You can change number of workspaces using &lt;strong&gt;CompizConfig Settings Manager&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install CompizConfig Settings Manager
    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt-get install compizconfig-settings-manager
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After installation, run CompizConfig. You can find it by typing Compiz after hitting Windows key button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Navigate to General -&amp;gt; General Options -&amp;gt; Desktop Size tab.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ubuntu-compiz/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In here, you can adjust number of horizontal and vertical virtual size.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now you can be able to navigate between workspaces using keyboard shortcut Ctrl + Alt + Arrow Keys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CompizConfig Settings Manager (CCSM) provides also a good way to divide your screen into 4 or more spaces. To enable this feature:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launch CCSM&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go Window Management category and click Grid.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ubuntu-compiz/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I like to divide the screen into 4 pieces. To do this select everything like below:
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ubuntu-compiz/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can see keyboard shortcuts to move pieces to desired locations in bindings tab.
 &lt;img src=&quot;/images/ubuntu-compiz/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the default shortcuts. For example, if you press Ctrl + Alt + 7, selected window moves to top left, or if you press Ctrl + Alt + 6, it moves to right. You can achieve this behaviour by dragging selected windows with mouse to right, left, bottom left, top left etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING:&lt;/strong&gt; The CompizConfig Settings Manager is a powerful application. You might break your desktop configuration by mistake. If you encounter problems after tweaking your setup with CompizConfig, you can reset settings by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ unity --reset
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CCSM has many to offer, but this post is limited with the features above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope thanks to this post, I can manage to make your Linux experience more enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/ubuntu-compiz/ubuntu-logo.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/ubuntu-compiz/ubuntu-logo.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Real AdBlock Extension</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/29/adblock.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Real AdBlock Extension" /><published>2019-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/29/adblock</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/29/adblock.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/adblock/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;AdBlock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the popular Adblock extensions like &lt;a href=&quot;https://getadblock.com&quot;&gt;AdBlock&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://adblockplus.org/&quot;&gt;AdBlock Plus&lt;/a&gt; actually doesn’t provide full protection of ads. They started their way to promising this ideology, but after 2015 they became part of ridicilious &lt;strong&gt;Acceptable Ads Program&lt;/strong&gt;, which basically means that you will still see some ads even if you use these extensions. I am sure you have already experienced this before. The reason behind this issue is the above Adblock extensions either purchased by advertisement agencies or they are getting paid by them. Yeah, I know this is annoying, but no worries. I have good news for you. I found a perfect AdBlock extension (at least for now) that blocks every advertisement. Its name is &lt;strong&gt;UBlock Origin&lt;/strong&gt;. It is compatible with almost all web browsers. To get more info about it, you can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UBlock_Origin&quot;&gt;UBlock Origin Wiki page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about the subject, you can see this amazing &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@trybravery/please-stop-using-adblock-but-not-why-you-think-13280e76c8e7&quot;&gt;Medium post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this will help!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/adblock/1.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/adblock/1.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Visual Studio Code: Free Source-Code Editor for All Languages</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/13/visual-studio-code.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Visual Studio Code: Free Source-Code Editor for All Languages" /><published>2019-10-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/13/visual-studio-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/13/visual-studio-code.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/visual-studio-code/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Visual Studio Code&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, I found a perfect source-code editor for myself thanks to my friend Austin (yeey!). Previously, I was using &lt;strong&gt;PyCharm&lt;/strong&gt; for Python and &lt;strong&gt;Qt Creator&lt;/strong&gt; for C++. However, switching between them was quite tiring. After lots of different editor trials, &lt;strong&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/strong&gt; saved me from all the trouble. It is a free source-code editor developed by Microsoft. It can be used in all Linux, macOS or Windows computers. It contains editor, debugging tool,  embedded git control and Github (my favorite property), syntax highlighting, intelligent code completion, snippets and much more than you expect from a code-editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download it using &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; link. After installation, I strongly recommend to follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/getstarted/tips-and-tricks&quot;&gt;tips and tricks page&lt;/a&gt;. This page will give you quick review of editor and introduce all the cool properties. You have to install different &lt;strong&gt;code extensions&lt;/strong&gt; to start coding such as Python one. To find out how to do it, see &lt;strong&gt;Extensions&lt;/strong&gt; section of tips and tricks page. Except from tips and tricks page, each language extension has its own getting started tutorial like &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/python/python-tutorial&quot;&gt;Getting Started with Python in VS Code&lt;/a&gt;. Before starting coding in a specific programming language, visit corresponding getting started page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, thanks to &lt;strong&gt;VS Code&lt;/strong&gt; , you can code and test (debug) your project in one window. It also allows you to upload your code to Github in the same window. Lastly, you can google different users’ preferences and favorite keyboard shortcuts like &lt;a href=&quot;https://vslive.com/Blogs/News-and-Tips/2015/04/5-VS-Keyboard-Shortcuts.aspx&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; to get best experience from the editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; If you have problems with multi-line selection short cut (Alt + Click) , that’s normal. This problem occured to me as well for Ubuntu 16.04. To fix this, you need to enable multi-cursor clicking by typing following command into the terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gsettings set org.gnome.desktop.wm.preferences mouse-button-modifier &quot;&amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;&quot;   
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy coding!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/visual-studio-code/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/visual-studio-code/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Robot Report: Website to Explore News related to Robotics Applications</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/30/robotreport.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Robot Report: Website to Explore News related to Robotics Applications" /><published>2019-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/30/robotreport</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/30/robotreport.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/robot-report/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Robot Report&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Robot Report&lt;/strong&gt; is an amazing robotics news website. If you are interested
in robotics, you should definitely check it out. It is different than other 
sources that I mentioned in my previous &lt;a href=&quot;https://samialperen.github.io/2019/03/19/robotics-resources.html&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;. This website focuses on newest robotics applications from business perspective. It introduces companies and their work related to robotics. Even if you are not interested in business side, I believe it is still useful to follow it in order to have a better understanding of your research and broaden your horizon. Checking coolest robots and autonomous systems in the morning while enjoying your coffee is a good start for the day :). You can check the website using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.therobotreport.com/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/robot-report/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/robot-report/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Jack London - Martin Eden Kitabı ve Sosyal Sınıflar Üzerine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/25/martin-eden.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack London - Martin Eden Kitabı ve Sosyal Sınıflar Üzerine" /><published>2019-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/25/martin-eden</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/25/martin-eden.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/martin-eden/martin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lecturer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack London. Uzun zamandır beni en çok etkileyen kitaplardan biri olan Martin Eden’in yazarı büyük üstad. Yaşadığı hayat hakkında bilgi edindikten sonra ayrı bir saygı duydum kendisine. Size de tanıtmak amaçlı çok kısa ondan bahsetmek istiyorum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack London yani gerçek adıyla John Griffith London, 1876 yılında San Francisco’da doğdu. Çocukluğu alabildiğine hareketli geçen ustanın en büyük zevki kitap okumaktı, ancak ailesinin güç koşullarda yaşaması yüzünden on dört yaşında okulu bırakıp bir konserve fabrikasında çalışmaya başladı. On altı yaşına geldiğinde San Francisco Körfezi’nde sokak çetelerine katılmanın yanı sıra, kıyı devriyesi olarak da görev yapmış biriydi. 1893’te, hem para kazanmak hem de maceraperest duygularını tatmin için fok avına çıkan bir gemiyle Japonya’ya kadar gitti. ABD’ye döndükten sonra da tüm ülkeyi baştan başa dolaştı. Ancak kitaplara ve okumaya adeta aşkla bağlıydı. İçinde ukte kalan eğitimine devam etmek için yoğun çalışmaların ardından California Üniversitesi’ne girmeyi başardı, fakat yine maddi zorluklar sebebiyle kısa sürede ayrılmak zorunda kaldı. 1897’de, Klondike’ta altın madeni bulunduğu haberi üzerine altın aramaya koyuldu. 1900’de öykülerinden oluşan ve ülke çapında tanınmasını sağlayan “The Son of the Wolf” adlı kitabı yayınladı. 1902’de Londra’ya gidip kenar mahallelerde yaşayan insanların hayatlarını inceleyen London’ın hayatı olaylar ve maceralarla doluydu. Güney denizlerinde dolaştı, Rus-Japon Savaşı’nda muhabirlik yaptı. Tüm bu yaşadığı olaylar ve edindiği deneyimler eserlerinin zeminini oluşturdu. 1916’da ise erken sayılabilecek bir yaşta California’da intihar ederek bu hayattan ayrıldı.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin Eden kitabı ise bana göre Jack London’ın en değerli eseri sayılabilecek ve kendi yaşantısından çok sayıda izler taşıyan bir otobiyografik romandır. London bu romanında burjuva gerçekliği karşısında sınıf atlamak isteyen genç bir yazar olan Martin Eden isimli bir roman kahramanının düştüğü trajik durumu harika bir şekilde resmetmiştir. London sanki bu romanında tüm düşüncelerini, söylediklerini, söylemek isteyip de söyleyemediklerini, insanlardan ve rezil dünya düzeninden nefretini Martin Eden karakteriyle anlatmak istemiştir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canım ailem zamanında bana hiç hissettirmemeye çalışsa da görece yoksul bir çocukluk geçirmiştim. İyi ki de öyle olmuş. Sonrasında da aldığım eğitimle o meşhur toplum basamaklarını çıkmaya başladım. Kendimi mümkün olduğunca geliştirmeye çalıştım. Mezuniyetime birkaç ay kalmıştı. O sıralar yarı zamanlı olarak meşhur beyaz yakalı kesimin arasında çalışıyordum. Zaten mezuniyete kadar birçok kez sorguladığım hayattaki kararlarımı tekrar sorgulamaya başlamıştım. Tam işte öyle bir dönemde Martin Eden’i okumuştum. Belki de böyle bir döneme denk geldiği için beni bu kadar etkiledi, bilemiyorum. Hala da şaşkınım aslında biraz. Benden 100 yıl önce yaşamış bir insanla benzer durumları yaşayıp benzer duyguları hissetmiştik. Kitapların gücüne bir kez daha inandım ve de bu dünyanın düzeninin kolay kolay değişmeyeceğine. Aradan 100 yıl geçmesine rağmen hala hiçbir gelişme olmamış gibi. Kendi hislerimi ve daha da fazlasını kitaptan alıntıladığım Jack London’ın sözleriyle daha iyi açıklarım sanıyorum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Elbette ne söylersem söyleyeyim saygı ve dikkatle dinliyorsunuz. Sizler çürümüş, haksız kazanç sağlayan insanlarsınız desem öfkeleneceğinize kem küm eder, söylediklerimde büyük bir doğruluk payı olduğunu kabul edersiniz. Peki neden? Ünlü olduğum için, çok param olduğu için. Martin Eden olduğum için değil, fena bir herif olmayan, hiç de aptal sayılamayacak Martin Eden olduğum için değil. Size kalkıp ayın yeşil peynirden yapıldığını söylesem hemen kalkıp bu görüşü benimsersiniz, ya da en azından karşı çıkmazsınız. Çünkü param var benim, hem de dağ gibi. Halbuki bunlar çok önceden kazanılmış şeylerdi; bana ayağınızın kiriymişim gibi davranıp üstüme tükürdüğünüz sırada bu işler bitmişti.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Kendisini çok yaşlı hissediyordu, eski günlerinin şu kayıtsız, gamsız genç yoldaşlarından yüzyıllarca daha yaşlı. Çok fazla, geri dönemeyecak kadar fazla uzaklaşmıştı onlardan. Onların, bir zamanlar kendisinin de katıldığı yaşam biçimi çok tatsız geliyordu şimdi. Düşkırıklığına uğramıştı. Bir yabancıya dönüşmüştü artık. Ucuz bira nasıl tatsız geldiyse bu insanların arkadaşlıkları da yavan geliyordu ona. Onların çok önlerindeydi. Aralarında bilmem kaç kitap açılmış duruyordu. Kendisini sürgüne göndermiş, engin bir bilgi dünyasında, bir daha yuvasına geri dönemeyecak kadar dolaşmıştı.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;” ‘Ne olmuş Amerika Birleşik Devletleri’ne?’ diye karşılık verdi Martin. ‘On üç koloni, yöneticilerini devirip Cumhuriyet dedikleri yönetimi kurdular. Köleler kendi kendilerinin efendisi oldu. Artık kılıçlı efendiler yoktu. Fakat, ne olursanız olun efendisiz kalamazsınız, bu yüzden yeni bir efendi tipi türedi. Bu seferkiler büyük, güçlü, soylu efendiler değil; örümcek gibi her şeyi saran, hileci tüccarlar ve tefecilerdi. Bunlar sizi yeniden köleleştirdi, ne var ki, gerçek, soylu efendinin kol kuvvetiyle yapacağı gibi mertçe ve açıkça değil; gizlice, örümcek gibi ağlar örerek, yaltaklanarak, tatlı dille yalanlar dökerek yaptılar. Bunlar sizin köle yargıçlarınızı satın aldılar, köle yasalarınızı bozdular, dahası sizin köle kızlarınızı ve oğullarınızı köle mülkiyetindekinden de beter bir dehşete sürüklediler. İki milyon çocuğunuz bugün, Amerika Birleşik Devletleri’nin ticaret oligarşisinin emrinde çalışıyor. Sizin gibi on milyon kölenin ne karnı doyuyor, ne de başını sokacak doğru düzgün bir yeri var.’ “&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Düşünüyorum da, saflık zamanlarımda, güzel evlerde oturan, öğrenim görmüş, bankalarda hesapları olan, yüksek tabakadan bu insanların bir şey olduğunu sanırdım.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;-“Ben bir Cumhuriyetçiyim” diyerek yumuşak bir şekilde araya girdi bay Morse. “Beni hangi sınıfa sokuyorsunuz?”
-“Ah, siz bilinçsiz bir uşaksınız.”
-“Uşak mı?”
-“Elbette, bir şirket için çalışıyorsunuz. Ne işçi sınıfındansınız ne de herhangi bir sabıkanız var. Gelirinizi, karısını dövenler ya da yankesiciler üzerinden kazanmıyorsunuz. Geçiminizi toplumun efendilerinden sağlıyorsunuz, bir insanı besleyen de o adamın efendisidir. Evet, siz bir uşaksınız. Sizi, hizmet ettiğiniz sermayenin çıkarlarını geliştirmek ilgilendirir.”
…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Bugüne kadar sürekli bir yer bulamamıştı kendine. Bulunduğu her yere ayak uydurmuş, çalışırken de oyun oynarken de sağlam durduğu, haklarını elde etmek ve saygı görmek için mücadelede kararlı ve usta olduğu için, her zaman ve her yerde gözde olmuştu. Ama hiçbir yerde kök salamamıştı. Kendini değil de çevresini tatmin etmek için yeterince uyum göstermişti. İçi her zaman bir rahatsızlık duygusuyla altüst olmuş, kulağı her zaman öteden gelen çağrıyı işitmiş, bütün hayatı kitapları, aşkı ve sanatı keşfedene kadar aramak ve dolaşmakla geçmişti.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Yoksulluğun hiç de sevimli bir şey olmadığını bilmekle birlikte, onda da yoksulluğun, onurunu ve ümidini kaybetmemiş herkesi başarıya doğru iten sivri bir mahmuz ve dolayısıyla sağlıklı bir şey olduğu yolundaki, o rahat orta sınıf inanışı vardı.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Ama ben benim. Kendi beğenimin, çoğunluğun beğenisine boyun eğmesine izin veremem. Eğer bir şeyden hoşlanmıyorsam ondan hoşlanmıyorumdur, hepsu bu; ve çoğunluk hoşlanıyor ya da hoşlandığını sanıyor diye, hoşlanıyormuş gibi yapmam için de tek bir neden yok. Hoşlandığım ve hoşlanmadığım şeyler konusunda modaya uymam.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Bir konunun üzerinde kuluçkaya yatıp onu iyice olgunlaştırdıktan sonra, hemen daktilo başına geçmeyi adet edinmişti. Yazının yayınlanmaması onu çok fazla rahatsız etmiyordu. Yazmak, dağınık düşünce dizilerini bir araya getirerek ve zihne yüklenen tüm verileri nihai bir genellemeye tabi tutarak yapılan uzun bir zihinsel sürecin doruk noktasıydı. Böyle bir makale yazmak, Martin’in zihninde yeni sorunlar ve malzemelere yer açmak amacıyla gerçekleştirdiği bilinçli bir çabaydı. Bu, bir bakıma, gerçek ya da hayali dertlerden bunalan ve sabırlı sessizliklerini zaman zaman bozup ‘diyeceklerini demeden’ susmayan insanların bildik alışkanlığına benziyordu.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Ama Rut’a duyduğu aşk, güzelliğe duyduğu aşkın da ötesindeydi. Aşkın dünyadaki en güzel şey olduğuna inanıyordu. Onda devrim yapan, onu kaba saba bir denizciden bir öğrenciye ve sanatçıya dönüştüren şey aşktı; bu yüzden aşk, ona göre, bilim-sanat-aşk üçgeninin en önde geleniydi.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her insanın başka bir insandan öğreneceği bir şeyler olduğunan inanan ben kendi elimizle yarattığımız bu sosyal normlardan ve sınıflardan toplum olarak kurtulacağımız günü iple çekiyorum, her ne kadar pek umutlu olmasam da. Buralara kadar okuyan olur mu bilmiyorum ama gelen kişiye de bir &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ituzi_-9RJI&quot;&gt;şarkı&lt;/a&gt; bırakayım madem. Sevgiyle kalın…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/martin-eden/martin.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/martin-eden/martin.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My Observations about Being a Good/Bad Lecturer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/22/lecturer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Observations about Being a Good/Bad Lecturer" /><published>2019-06-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/22/lecturer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/22/lecturer.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/lecturer/college-lecture.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lecturer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I would like to share my observations about lecturers I encountered throughout my undergraduate life in Electrical and Electronics Engineering. Although, I really enjoy being an engineer and I chose my field on purpose, there were only few lecturers whose teaching style is really good. I am especially thankful to &lt;strong&gt;Prof. Umut Orguner&lt;/strong&gt; and his perfect teaching style. I hope I can be as good as him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, here are some effective and useful methods my professors use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the lectures (like 5-10 minutes), reminding what we did in the last lecture and then smoothly switching to that day’s lecture. In this way, even if I couldn’t revise previous lecture, I can still understand that day’s lecture clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Asking students whether they have any questions regarding the content by pausing intentionally between different parts of the lecture.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Of course, having a readable handwriting :)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Explaining the lecture in a simple way and without assuming students already know it. For example, while studying state space representation, reminding how to take 3x3 matrices inverse instead of saying “You have already learnt this!”.
If the part that students need to remember is too long, providing enough extra study material like handsheet for students to remember.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Providing an overall picture of the course content and connecting different subjects of the lecture smoothly. It is important to know name of the concept/method/problem you are studying.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If possible, giving a real life example regarding the content. Even if real life problem is much more complicated, knowing physical correspondence helps better understanding and motivates students.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Being honest to students. Instead of pretending to know everything, admitting you don’t know that particular thing and willing to learn more for the next lecture (if it is related).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sharing some funny and informative videos regarding lecture (if possible) at the last part of the lecture. We all know that last minutes of the lecture might be boring. In this way, I believe both students and lecturer be happy. During the time that I was taking an &lt;strong&gt;Electromechanical Energy Conversion&lt;/strong&gt; course, our lecturer shows us videos related to course content like magnets, dc motors, electric motor etc. at the of the lecture. I remember how much I enjoy during that time. Our lecturer name is &lt;strong&gt;Mr. Ozan Keysan&lt;/strong&gt;. He is also a great lecturer. &lt;a href=&quot;http://keysan.me/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is his blog address.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Providing problem sets with solutions to help students apprehend the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sharing previous years exams to give an idea about structure of the exam.
I believe even one example is enough.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Giving challenging homeworks, but asking easy questions in the exam. In my opinion, this is really a good strategy since you learn the subject quite well thanks to homeworks, and thanks to relatively easy exams, you don’t concern about grades and only focus to learn. I am grateful to &lt;strong&gt;Mr. Mert Ankarali&lt;/strong&gt; for this. You can visit his blog using &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.metu.edu.tr/mertan/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I personally prefer traditional classroom style where lecturer uses blackboard and students take notes. However, sometimes it is necessary to use some visualization to not waste too much time for drawing to board. For this style, providing lecture notes with some intentional blanks for students to fill works very well. For example, in &lt;strong&gt;Signal and Systems&lt;/strong&gt; course, we had printed lecture notes whose 70% was already filled, but some parts were empty like answers of the examples and some warnings. Lecturer also used the same lecture notes and as students we were only writing necessary parts. In this way, we can follow the lecture easily, and we have wonderful and complete lecture notes. For me, this method is quite beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Preparing lecture content weekly as well to have comprehensive knowledge of subjects and adjusting lecture time perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sharing anonymous questionnaires about course to get feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, good lecturers I encountered can be counted on the fingers of one hand. Most of the time, I face with really bad lecturers. Either they really know the subject, but suck at teaching or they don’t care teaching at all. Of course, we can still learn from them what we shouldn’t do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some common characteristics of bad lecturers I have seen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using the same voice tone throughout the lecture, which makes students sleepy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Following &lt;strong&gt;Powerpoint Slides&lt;/strong&gt; blindly i.e. only reading what is written in slides.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wasting too much time on unimportant things in the lecture. For example, stucking at unnecessary and unrelated student questions and spending too much time to answer them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Deeply explaining concepts that are already covered by other lectures. I can give an example to describe this point. In one course spending two weeks to explain linearization procedure (which is just a step for that course) while in the same semester there is another course that we have already learnt linearization procedure deeply and very well. Instead, lecturer should shortly remind it in 10-20 minutes. It is important to analyze the curriculum and be aware of what and how much students know.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Related to previous point, not following other courses of students in same semester and pretending that your course is the only course that students are dealing with. This causes to having extremely heavy workload in specific weeks and reduces motivation of students. Believe me, as students we always appreciate professors who are aware of our situation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pretending to know everything related to course and not giving students a chance to ask questions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Making fun of students’ questions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Preparing exams that are almost not related at all what is studied in classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This point happens especially for laboratory courses. Teaching simple stuff in lab hours and requiring extremely difficult lab projects from students to complete. I am aware of the fact that university is a place for students to make research and learn by themselves, but still keeping everything to students doesn’t make sense at all. I remember that in our digital electronics laboratory, we studied simple hello world or if-else structure in verilog language, but image recognition algorithm was given as a term project which should be implemented in FPGA using Verilog. That was the first time we programmed FPGA and thanks to this project I literally hated electronics courses.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, all these points are relative. Maybe other students disagree with me, but anyway, I wanted to share my observations to not forget what I went through in my undergraduate life. Hopefully, I will not do the things I don’t like when I was student.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/lecturer/college-lecture.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/lecturer/college-lecture.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">TransferWise: Send Money Abroad at Lowest Possible Cost</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/14/transferwise.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TransferWise: Send Money Abroad at Lowest Possible Cost" /><published>2019-06-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/14/transferwise</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/14/transferwise.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/transferwise/tw.webp&quot; alt=&quot;TransferWise&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TransferWise&lt;/strong&gt; is a UK-based money transfer service which allows its users to transfer money internationally at lowest possible transfer fee. It achieves this by using two local transfers instead of one international transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you want to send money to USA from UK. You can easily achieve this using TransferWise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First you need to sign up a new TransferWise account via &lt;a href=&quot;https://transferwise.com/&quot;&gt;TransferWise website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Website is quite easy to catch. Follow the steps named &lt;strong&gt;Send Money&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Enter the amount that you want to send. In this case, you will use your pound account in UK, so you will be converting pound to dolar. For example, you want to send 500$ to a friend in USA. As you can see in the below picture, for this you need to send 397.13£ and transfer fee is only 2.22£.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/transferwise/tw3.png&quot; alt=&quot;TransferWise 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After that you can click &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;. You will need to enter all details related to the bank account you want to send the money.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Transaction&lt;/strong&gt; step, system will give you a local &lt;strong&gt;IBAN&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Transaction Number&lt;/strong&gt; that you are going to transfer the money in. In this way, you are actually going to make a local transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After this step, all you need to do is wait. System will send you an e-mail that confirms that they receive your money. After that you are gonna get another e-mail that confirms that your money is arrived to USA.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a simple diagram that shows how system works:
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/transferwise/tw2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TransferWise 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to worry about the safety of the system. I personally used it and it works perfect. You can further search Google for user comments about TransferWise. Thanks to TransferWise, you don’t need to pay 45$ transaction fee for a 500$ transfer :) Boo &lt;strong&gt;Western Union&lt;/strong&gt;!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/transferwise/tw.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/transferwise/tw.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Berlin Living &amp;amp; Travel Guide</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/02/berlin-guide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Berlin Living &amp; Travel Guide" /><published>2019-06-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/02/berlin-guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/02/berlin-guide.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/reichstag.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reichstag&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I will try to give all necessary tips about living in Berlin, and I will also provide an awesome travel guide for you to discover the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;accommodation--transportation&quot;&gt;Accommodation &amp;amp; Transportation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are coming to Berlin as a tourist, accommodation won’t cause any problem for you. There are many hotels or hostels in the Berlin.  Unfortunately, I won’t be able to give specific hostel/hotel names. I stayed at &lt;strong&gt;Pegasus Hostel Berlin&lt;/strong&gt; (near to Berlin Ostbahnhof) during my first visit to Berlin as a tourist, and it was okay. I can say that staying in a hotel which is close to city center would be beneficial for you. For this purpose, you may want to stay in &lt;strong&gt;Mitte&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Kreuzberg&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Schöneberg&lt;/strong&gt; districts of Berlin. Nonetheless, if you stay another district, that’s okay as well since public transportation is quite advanced in Berlin and you can go anywhere you like using public transportation. During weekends, &lt;strong&gt;SBahns&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Ubahns&lt;/strong&gt; works all day including night. During weekdays, they are closed after some time at night, but there are &lt;strong&gt;Night Buses&lt;/strong&gt; in the same routes. By the way, I should mention that &lt;strong&gt;Buses&lt;/strong&gt; always work 24 hour. Hence, transportation in Berlin never disappoints you. There are no ticket barriers in metro. You should buy appropriate ticket for you. Officers perform ticket check during the week at random times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/districts.png&quot; alt=&quot;Berlin Districts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For navigation, I prefer to use &lt;strong&gt;Google Maps&lt;/strong&gt;. I definitely suggest it for you. You can see all possible routes in real time. Trust me, you are going to need this, since there are many SBahn, UBahn and Bus routes. It is quite easy to get lost, especially in first days :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/google-maps.png&quot; alt=&quot;Berlin Districts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;supermarkets&quot;&gt;Supermarkets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many different supermarkets in Berlin. &lt;strong&gt;Aldi&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Lidl&lt;/strong&gt; are the cheapest ones. &lt;strong&gt;Edeka&lt;/strong&gt; could be an alternative option as well. Of course, generally the closest market to your house is always the best, but they might be small like &lt;strong&gt;Penny&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Netto&lt;/strong&gt;. For bigger supermarkets, you can check &lt;strong&gt;Rewe&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Kaufland&lt;/strong&gt;. However, as I mentioned, they don’t have too many branch like others. If you are looking for Turkish supermarkets, &lt;strong&gt;Eurogida&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Bolu&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Nazar&lt;/strong&gt; etc. would be a perfect option. You can get more information about supermarkets visiting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archer-relocation.com/a-complete-guide-to-supermarkets-in-berlin/&quot;&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Germans are not very used to have quite big shopping malls like us, so if you are looking for someplace like that, you could be dissappointed. As far as I know, &lt;strong&gt;Kaufhaus Des Westens a.k.a. Kadewe&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Bikini Berlin&lt;/strong&gt; are the only shopping malls in Berlin. I personally don’t recommend to visit for shopping since the prices are unnecessarily expensive. You can visit for touristic purposes, and I will mention it in the following sections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/kadewe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kadewe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost all supermarkets are closed on Sunday like every country in Europe, so be aware of that and get prepared. There are some places called &lt;strong&gt;Spätkauf&lt;/strong&gt; to buy simple stuff. You can also use them in late night. As you expect, they are more expensive than normal supermarkets, but not too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/spatkauf.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Spatkauf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also visit traditional &lt;strong&gt;flea markets&lt;/strong&gt;. They are like bazaars and set up in public parks. You can discover incredible things with incredible prices. If you are looking for some souivenirs for your lovings, flea markets would be perfect place for you. You can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visitberlin.de/en/blog/top-11-berlin-flea-markets&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about flea markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/fleamarket.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flea Market&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this section, I can talk about &lt;strong&gt;recyling&lt;/strong&gt; lastly. In Germany, you need to seperate your trash properly for recyling like every coutry. Of course, the seperations differ from country to country, but it is not going to be problem for you. The thing which is different is the term &lt;strong&gt;Pfand&lt;/strong&gt;. Whenever, you buy something to drink, you will see that there is an extra fee called &lt;strong&gt;Pfand&lt;/strong&gt;. It means refundable. You can return these items to the places called &lt;strong&gt;Pfand Station&lt;/strong&gt;, you can get your money back. You can find these stations mostly in bigger supermarkets. Moreover, when you are at outside, don’t surprise if you see somebody picking up all the &lt;strong&gt;pfand-able&lt;/strong&gt; bottles around. Some people earn their money using this way. In short, it is good for both environment and your pocket. You can follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archer-relocation.com/how-to-recycle-in-germany/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to get more information about recyling in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/pfand-station.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Pfand Station&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mobile-operators-and-internet&quot;&gt;Mobile Operators and Internet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are going to stay in Germany for a short time, it is wise to buy a prepaid simcard rather than making contract. There are many different prepaid simcard options with different mobile operators. When I was in Berlin, I used &lt;strong&gt;Ayyildiz&lt;/strong&gt; mobile operator with an offering 15 GB Internet per month for 15€. It was more than enough for me. You can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://budgettraveller.org/travelling-to-germany-tips-for-getting-mobile-internet-access/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to learn more. If you are going to stay longer, you might want to make a contract. Please follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.movingto-berlin.com/mobile-contract/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to see a comparison between different mobile operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; One good thing about Berlin is that there is &lt;strong&gt;Free Wifi&lt;/strong&gt; in Ubahn stations and it is quite fast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Internet usage (both mobile or home), you need to be careful. You shouldn’t use Torrent or IPTV or you shouldn’t make illegal downloadings. Germany is quite strict about illegal downloadings. If you get caught, you might have to pay a fine (more than 1000€), so please be careful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discover-the-city&quot;&gt;Discover the City&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-&quot;&gt;1-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you should do to learn more about the City is attending a tour. You can attend &lt;strong&gt;SANDEMANs Free Tour of Berlin&lt;/strong&gt; which takes 3 hour. If you like it, you can take other paid tours as well. You can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neweuropetours.eu/sandemans-tours/berlin/free-tour-of-berlin/&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt; to learn tour dates and hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tour starts from &lt;strong&gt;Starbucks at Brandenburg Gate&lt;/strong&gt;. Look out people with &lt;strong&gt;Red Umbrella&lt;/strong&gt;, they are the guides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/brandenburg-gate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Brandenburg Gate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tour route may vary from guide to guide, but you will see the main tourist attractions like &lt;strong&gt;Memorial to the Murdered Jews of Europe (Holocaust Memorial)&lt;/strong&gt;,  &lt;strong&gt;Some Parts of Berlin Wall&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Checkpoint Charlie&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Gendarmenmarkt&lt;/strong&gt;. The tour will end at &lt;strong&gt;Bebelplatz&lt;/strong&gt;. This tour is really a good way to make a quick start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/holocaust-memorial.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Holocaust Memorial&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/checkpoint-charlie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Checkpoint Charlie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/gendarmenmarkt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gendarmenmarkt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/bebelplatz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bebelplatz&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-&quot;&gt;2-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can visit &lt;strong&gt;Mauerpark&lt;/strong&gt; on Sundays. There are karaoke, street performance and lots of fun. It is definitely a great way to spend a lovely Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/mauerpark.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mauerpark 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/mauerpark2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Mauerpark 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/mauerpark3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Mauerpark 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-&quot;&gt;3-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;strong&gt;Klunkerkranich&lt;/strong&gt; to watch the sunset over the rooftops of Berlin. It is a rooftop bar with a fantastic view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/klunkerkranich.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Klunkerkranich&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-&quot;&gt;4-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;strong&gt;Kaiser Wilhelm Memorial Church&lt;/strong&gt; which is damaged during the World War 2. You can enjoy the view from the terrace of &lt;strong&gt;Motel One&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Monkey Bar&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;NENI BERLIN&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/kaiserwilhelm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kaiser Wilhelm Memorial Church&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-&quot;&gt;5-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;strong&gt;East Side Gallery&lt;/strong&gt;: the longest air gallery in the world. Take a long walk along the East Side Gallery to learn the history of Berlin Wall and see amazing art work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/east-side-gallery.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;East Side Gallery&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that you can use beautiful &lt;strong&gt;Oberbaum Bridge&lt;/strong&gt; to cross the river. This bridge will provide you amazing background for a new profile picture :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/oberbraum-bridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Oberbaum Bridge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a hamburger restaurant named &lt;strong&gt;Burgermeister&lt;/strong&gt; at the end of Oberbaum Bridge. Their hamburgers and fries are delicious, but I should warn you about long waiting line. They have another shop in Kreuzberg. There is generally less people there, so you won’t need a lot. Nonetheless, I prefer this one because while eating your hamburger, you can enjoy the amazing view of &lt;strong&gt;East Side Gallery&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Oberbaum Bridge&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/burger-meister.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Burgermeister&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/burgermeister-view.png&quot; alt=&quot;Burgermeister View&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-&quot;&gt;6-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;strong&gt;Kruezberg Canal (Landwehr Canal/Urbanhafen)&lt;/strong&gt; and embrace the nature. Great place to take your drink and socialize with your friends. You can also visit &lt;strong&gt;Admiral Bridge&lt;/strong&gt; in the same area. It offers great atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/landwehr1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Kreuzberg Canal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/landwehr2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Kreuzberg Canal 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/admiral-bridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Admiral Bridge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/landwehr3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Kreuzberg Canal 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-&quot;&gt;7-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berlin offers various cafes, pubs, clubs. Here are some near &lt;strong&gt;Görlitzer Park&lt;/strong&gt;. However, you should be careful and stay away from the park itself. Generally the park is unfortunately known for drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birgit &amp;amp; Beer&lt;/strong&gt; is a beer garden with exotic ambience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/birgitandbeer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Birgit &amp;amp; Beer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das Edelweiss&lt;/strong&gt; holds great jazz sessions.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/dasedelweiss.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Das Edelweiss&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;800px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mano Cafe&lt;/strong&gt; is a cosy place with vintage aura and enough space for small crowds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/manocafe.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mano Cafe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bite Club&lt;/strong&gt; holds an open-air food festival in summer months. You should visit if you like street food. Check &lt;a href=&quot;http://biteclub.de/&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/biteclub.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bite Club&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Club der Visionaere&lt;/strong&gt; is a riverside bar with electronic music and parties at nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/clubdervisionere.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Club der Visionaere&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-&quot;&gt;8-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Viktoriapark&lt;/strong&gt; is a great public park with waterfalls and viewpoints to relax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/viktoriapark.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Viktoriapark&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-&quot;&gt;9-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schlachtensee&lt;/strong&gt; is always a good idea to run away from the city. If you go summer, you will see that a lot of people swim in this lake. If you like biking, visiting this lake by bike would be perfect for you. If you feel a bit lazy, you can take your bike with you to SBahn/Ubahn and use your bike only to discover the lake. However, check that your train ticket involves the right to carry bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/schlachtensee.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Schlachtensee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/schlachtensee2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Schlachtensee 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-&quot;&gt;10-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hackesche Höfe&lt;/strong&gt; is composed of historical small and sweet courtyards. After that you can taste rose shaped delicicious ice-creams of &lt;strong&gt;Amorino&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/hackeschehofe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hackesche Höfe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/hackeschehofe2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Hackesche Höfe 2&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/hackeschehofe3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Amorino Icecreams&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;11-&quot;&gt;11-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if they are expensive, it is still delightful to visit shopping malls &lt;strong&gt;KaDeWe&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Bikini Berlin&lt;/strong&gt;. I personally like foodhall and suparmarket part of KaDeWe. Shops in Bikini Berlin are also charming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/bikiniberlin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bikini Berlin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/kadewe2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;KaDeWe Food Hall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;12-&quot;&gt;12-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a small church named &lt;strong&gt;Nikolaikirche&lt;/strong&gt;. Behind this course, there exists a small area named &lt;strong&gt;Nikolaiviertel&lt;/strong&gt;. I really like narrow paths in this area with humble cafes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/nikolaiviertel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nikolaiviertel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/nikolaiviertel2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nikolaiviertel 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/nikolaiviertel3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nikolaiviertel 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/nikolaiviertel4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nikolaiviertel 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;13-&quot;&gt;13-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clärchens Ballroom&lt;/strong&gt; could be a satisfactory choice for people who are looking for a classy German restaurant with live music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/clarchens.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Clärchens Ballroom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;14-&quot;&gt;14-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kastanienallee&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the hit regions of Berliners. You can find lots of cafe, restaurant throughout this region. It also provides great street views with fascinating architectures. Whether you are with your friend or alone, it is always a good idea to go for a walk in this region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/kastanialle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kastanienallee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/kastanialle2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kastanienallee 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/kastanialle3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Kastanienallee 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/kastanialle4.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Kastanienallee 4&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;15-&quot;&gt;15-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can visit &lt;strong&gt;Drachenberg&lt;/strong&gt; which offers a fantactic top-view of the City. After that you can go and visit &lt;strong&gt;Teufelsberg Spy Towers&lt;/strong&gt; which was a listening station during the Cold War.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/teufelsberg.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Drachenberg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/teufelsberg2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Drachenberg 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/teufelsberg3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Teufelsberg Spy Towers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/teufelsberg4.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Teufelsberg Spy Towers 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/teufelsberg5.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Teufelsberg Spy Towers 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;16-&quot;&gt;16-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germany Parliament Building &lt;strong&gt;Reichstag&lt;/strong&gt;, which is still actively used, must be seen. If you book in advance (like 2-3 week before), you can visit characteristic glass dome &lt;strong&gt;Reichstag Dome&lt;/strong&gt; for free. It is the only place in Reichstag that Hitler never stepped foot in. You can also get quite informative audio guide for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/reichstag.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reichstag&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/reichstagdome.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reichstag Dome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/reichstagdome.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Reichstag Dome 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;17-&quot;&gt;17-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holzmarkt&lt;/strong&gt; is an excellent place near the river which has very exotic pubs and cafes. I like the bar &lt;strong&gt;Holzmarkt Pampa&lt;/strong&gt;’s atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/holzmarkt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Holzmarkt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/holzmarkt2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Holzmarkt 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/holzmarkt3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Holzmarkt 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;18-&quot;&gt;18-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can visit rococo style &lt;strong&gt;Charlottenburg Palace&lt;/strong&gt; and its huge garden. Although there is an entrance fee for palace, beautiful garden can be discovered for free. Moreover, you can also visit all the palace for free in the last Sunday of each month. There is no nearby market to the Palace, so it is highly recommended that take your snacks and drinks with you before coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/charlottenburg.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Charlottenburg Palace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/charlottenburg2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Charlottenburg Palace 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;19-&quot;&gt;19-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cafe am Engelbecken&lt;/strong&gt; is lovely, cosy and calming cafe which is located near a small lake. The prices are not too expensive especially if you think about its location. It might be a perfect place to read your book while enjoying your coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/engelbecken2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cafe am Engelbecken&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/engelbecken.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cafe am Engelbecken 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;20-&quot;&gt;20-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a boat ride, instead of paying money for touristic cruise tours, you can use &lt;strong&gt;BVG’s Ferry&lt;/strong&gt; with your BVG ticket that you use in SBahns, UBahns and buses. There is a great route for this purpose. You can go &lt;strong&gt;Wansee&lt;/strong&gt; using SBahn and then you can walk just 2 minutes to &lt;strong&gt;Wansee Station&lt;/strong&gt;. Take &lt;strong&gt;BVG F10 Ferry&lt;/strong&gt; which goes to &lt;strong&gt;Station Kladow&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Kladow&lt;/strong&gt; will welcome you with a great view and lovely cafes. After getting some snacks and drinks from supermarkets near Kladow Station, you can follow &lt;strong&gt;Imchenallee&lt;/strong&gt; street throughout river. If you are willing to go further, you deserve to enjoy a nice coffee in &lt;strong&gt;Sommercafé im Landhausgarten Dr. Max Fraenkel&lt;/strong&gt;. You can either walk or get on a bicycle, but if you are on foot, then it is better to return to Station Kladow by taking bus from the nearest bus stop &lt;strong&gt;Hottengrund&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t forget to check the last take off time of the ferrys from Station Kladow to Station Wansee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/wansee.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Station Wansee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/wansee4.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Station Wansee 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/wansee2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Station Kladow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/wansee3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Station Kladow 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/wansee5.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Imchenallee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/wansee6.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Imchenallee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After returning Station Wansee, you can appreciate pleasing evening with sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/sunset.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset at Wansee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/sunset2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset at Wansee 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;21-&quot;&gt;21-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treptower Park&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the biggest public parks in Berlin. In the middle of the park, there is &lt;strong&gt;Soviet War Memorial&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a cemetery for Soviet Soldiers in WW2. You can take pedal boats from here. There is a nearby &lt;strong&gt;Burger King&lt;/strong&gt; which offers great view of the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/treptow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Treptower Park&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/treptow2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Treptower Park 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/treptow3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Treptower Park 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/treptow4.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Treptower Park 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;22-&quot;&gt;22-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill your stomach with yummy street food in &lt;strong&gt;Markthalle Neun&lt;/strong&gt; on Thursdays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/markthalle.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Markthalle Neun&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/markthalle2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Markthalle Neun 2&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;23-&quot;&gt;23-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fastfood chain &lt;strong&gt;RISA&lt;/strong&gt; is like &lt;strong&gt;KFC&lt;/strong&gt;, but with better taste and cheaper price. Just try it and you are going to agree with me :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/risa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RISA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;24-&quot;&gt;24-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are extremely many museums in Berlin. Specify the ones that get your attention. No need to say that &lt;strong&gt;Museum Island&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Berliner Dome&lt;/strong&gt; must be seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Museum Island&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Berliner Dom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topography of Terror:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;ToT&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum4.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;ToT 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DDR Museum:&lt;/strong&gt; Interactive museum to learn about the life in East Germany before the fall of Berlin Wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/ddr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DDR&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tränenpalast:&lt;/strong&gt; This small free museum shows the tragedy that has happened in the border of East-West Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum5.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Tranenpalast&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medizinhistorisches Museum:&lt;/strong&gt; Provides a path through medical history over past 300 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum6.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;medizin&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum7.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;medizin 2&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jewish Museum:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum8.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;jewish&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum9.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;jewish 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural History Museum:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/naturalhistory.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;natural&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/naturalhistory2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;natural2&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an annual event called &lt;strong&gt;Long Night Museum&lt;/strong&gt;. During one day, almost all museums in Berlin is open during the night as well. You can visit them with only one ticket. There is also shuttles between major museums. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lange-nacht-der-museen.de/en/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the event link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;25-&quot;&gt;25-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Botanical Gardens&lt;/strong&gt; is worth to visit if you like the nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum9.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;botanical&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum10.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;botanical 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;26-&quot;&gt;26-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is impossible to not mention &lt;strong&gt;Tiergarten&lt;/strong&gt;, the biggest public park of the Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/tier.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tiergarten&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;27-&quot;&gt;27-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;strong&gt;Urban Nation Streetart Museum&lt;/strong&gt; near &lt;strong&gt;Nollendorfplatz&lt;/strong&gt;. You are going to see wonderful pieces even in the street of museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/urban.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;urban&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/urban2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;urban 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/urban3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;urban 3&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;28-&quot;&gt;28-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tempelhofer Feld&lt;/strong&gt; is a former airport which was built under Nazi regime. It is now a public park. It is definitely great place for bicyling, skating or flying a kite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/tempelhof.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Tempelhof&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/tempelhof2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Tempelhof2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;29-&quot;&gt;29-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sachsenhausen Concentration Camp&lt;/strong&gt; is the nearest concentration camp to Berlin. It is only one hour way and you can use Sbahn to arrive here. It must be seen to embrace humanity more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/nazicamp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nazi Camp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/nazicamp2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Nazi Camp 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/nazicamp3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Nazi Camp 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;30-&quot;&gt;30-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ritter Sport&lt;/strong&gt; is a German chocolate brand. It offers many different types of chocolates. For me, it is the best for its price. You can find these chocolates in every supermarket. However, they have their own shop named &lt;strong&gt;Ritter Sport Bunte Schokowelt Berlin&lt;/strong&gt;. If you want to buy lots of chocolate, this shop is the right place. You can also design your own chocolate in here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/ritter2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ritter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/ritter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ritter 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bonus&quot;&gt;BONUS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berlin is a great city with so much to offer for every kind of people. There are always an event, festival, concert etc. Follow Facebook events related to Berlin and use &lt;strong&gt;MeetUp&lt;/strong&gt; application to socialize and find events according to your interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Event&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Event2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Event3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Event4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Event5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event4.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Event4.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Event7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Event6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/berlin-guide/reichstag.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/berlin-guide/reichstag.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Get Canada Study Permit? (Kanada Öğrenci Vizesi Nasıl Alınır?)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/15/canada-studypermit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Get Canada Study Permit? (Kanada Öğrenci Vizesi Nasıl Alınır?)" /><published>2019-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/15/canada-studypermit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/15/canada-studypermit.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/canada-flag.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Canada Flag&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;general-information-and-required-documents&quot;&gt;General Information and Required Documents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are going to Canada for educational purposes like language school, undergraduate/graduate studies, and you are going to stay more than 6 months, then you need to take a &lt;strong&gt;Study Permit&lt;/strong&gt;. Of course, this depends on your home country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I am going to share my experience about getting Canada Study Permit. My hometown is &lt;strong&gt;Turkey&lt;/strong&gt;, so all information in here will be related to application from Turkey. Yet, general procedure is pretty much same. Only some documents might differ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/services/study-canada/study-permit.html&quot;&gt;Canada Immigration and Citizenship website&lt;/a&gt; as a main source. You should check it out for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, the school that you are accepted in Canada should be one of the designated learning institutions (DLI). According to the Canada Immigration and Citizenship website, a designated learning institution (DLI) is a school approved by a provincial or territorial government to host international students. You will need an acceptance letter from a DLI. Check whether your school is a DLI or not using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/services/study-canada/study-permit/prepare/designated-learning-institutions-list.html&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prepared my documents by taking reference &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/services/study-canada/study-permit/prepare/get-documents.html&quot;&gt;Canada Immigration and Citizenship website document list&lt;/a&gt;. Here are the necessary documents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proof of acceptance (Acceptance letter from a DLI)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Valid Passport and Old Passports (if you have)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One Digital Biometric Photo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proof of financial support:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A letter from the school giving you money. It should include the amount of funding you will get with tuition fee. (personally I had just one acceptance letter from the university. The funding amount is written on that, but Tuition isn’t)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My bank statements for the past 6 months&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sponsorship Letter from my father. &lt;a href=&quot;/static/canada-studypermit/sponsorship-template.docx&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the template to download. Change it according to your situation. I just provided it to give you a clue about its format.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My sponsor’s 6 month salary roll&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My sponsor’s bank statements (I didn’t provide)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;House Title Deed (if applicable)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Vehicle License (if applicable)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Letter of explanation: This is probably the most important document of yours. You need to clearly explain why you want to take study permit. You can attach any file you want to letter of explanation. Please don’t forget that this file is the only thing that gives you a chance to convince visa officer. It is stated as optional in the website, but I personally believe that it should be MUST! &lt;a href=&quot;/static/canada-studypermit/letter-of-explanation-template.docx&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the template to download. I attached below files to my letter of explanation:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Student Certificate&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;TOEFL Score&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;GRE Score&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Transcript&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Curriculum Vitae (CV)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Criminal Record (e-devlet)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Letter of Acceptance from Universities in other countries&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My previous passport&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My National ID (Turkey)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Minimum amount of money that you need to show for financial support is stated as Tuition + 10.000 CAD per year for one  student (Outside Quebec, 2019 Year). You should check Canada Immigration website above to see the required amount applicable for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; I personally didn’t provide any accommodation arrangement or flight tickets to get study permit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-apply&quot;&gt;How to Apply?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can apply for study permit in either &lt;strong&gt;online&lt;/strong&gt; or via &lt;strong&gt;VFS Global&lt;/strong&gt;. VFS Global is a legal intermediary establishment for Canada visa applications. Depending on your country, there might be another establishment rather than VFS Global.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I preferred to apply online since it is easy and you don’t have to give extra money to VFS Global. To apply online, first visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/services/application/account.html&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; link to create an account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sign Up Options&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two different sign up options: via &lt;strong&gt;Sign-in Partner&lt;/strong&gt; or via &lt;strong&gt;GCkey&lt;/strong&gt;. Sign-in Partner option is for the people who have a Canadian bank account. Use GCkey if you don’t have Canadian bank account or a partner bank account (which is probably your case if you are applying in Turkey).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;GCkey Sign Up&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During sign-up process, please be careful and provide necessary information correctly. Moreover, you need to create some security questions with answers for yourself. These questions and answers will be super important since you are going to use one of them at each time you enter the &lt;strong&gt;CiC&lt;/strong&gt; website. Therefore, don’t forget to take a note!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After signing in to your account, you need to create a new application. For this purpose, scroll down &lt;strong&gt;Start an Application&lt;/strong&gt; section and click &lt;strong&gt;Apply to come to Canada&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Start an Application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Visitor visa, study and/or work permit&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Study Permit Button&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you will need to fill out a survey to find out whether you are eligible to apply a study permit. This survey at the end creates a personalized document checklist for your account to upload necessary documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Application Survey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can save your answers and exit the survey anytime you want using &lt;strong&gt;Save and Exit Questionnaire&lt;/strong&gt; button at the bottom left. You can proceed next pages of survey using &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt; button at the bottom right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After completion of the survey, you should be able to see &lt;strong&gt;Documents to Submit&lt;/strong&gt; page like below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Documents to Submit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there are some other extra documents to upload:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application for Study Permit Made Outside of Canada (IMM1294)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Family Information (IMM5645)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Schedule 1 - Application for a Temporary Resident Visa Made Outside Canada (IMM5257)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download these documents by clicking document name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; You need to use new versions of &lt;strong&gt;Adobe Reader&lt;/strong&gt; to open and edit these documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; You need to upload &lt;strong&gt;Letter of Explanation&lt;/strong&gt; with its attachments to &lt;strong&gt;Client Information&lt;/strong&gt; part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After uploading all the documents, you will pay the visa application fee online and your application will be completed. When there is an update about your document, you will receive an email to check your &lt;strong&gt;CiC&lt;/strong&gt; account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To read the message, you need to enter your account and click &lt;strong&gt;Check Full Application Status&lt;/strong&gt; under &lt;strong&gt;Vie the applications you submitted&lt;/strong&gt; part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Check Full Applcation Status&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scrool down to &lt;strong&gt;Messages about your application&lt;/strong&gt; part and you will see the messages regarding your application. Click them to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/7.png&quot; alt=&quot;CiC Messages&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t been in Canada before, you may need to give &lt;strong&gt;Biometrics&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks to survey you have filled out, if you need to give biometrics, you are going to pay necessary &lt;strong&gt;Biometrics Fee&lt;/strong&gt; and after a few days (for ex, 1 day for my application) you will receive a message &lt;strong&gt;Biometrics Collection Letter&lt;/strong&gt; which requests biometrics of yours. You need to visit &lt;strong&gt;VFS Global&lt;/strong&gt; to give biometrics. All detailed information is covered in received &lt;strong&gt;Biometrics Collection Letter&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After giving Biometrics, there is nothing to do left. All you need to do is to wait. I got my study permit at my first attempt and it took exactly &lt;strong&gt;1 Month&lt;/strong&gt;. I paid &lt;strong&gt;150 CaD Study Permit Fee&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;85 CaD Biometrics Fee&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for this post. I wish you can get your visa at the first time you applied. If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to use comment section below. Study permit application might seem a bit complicated at first, but trust me it is not. Start to prepare documents early and don’t spend money on Visa Consultancy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/canada-studypermit/canada-flag.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/canada-studypermit/canada-flag.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>