<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-05T10:52:20+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Personal Blog of Sami Alperen Akgün</title><subtitle>Welcome to my personal blog! In this blog, I will try to share my experience and thoughts about academic life, travel, literature technology, music, movies and TV-series. You can use/share any information in here as long as you provide reference. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Jack London - Martin Eden Kitabı ve Sosyal Sınıflar Üzerine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/25/martin-eden.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack London - Martin Eden Kitabı ve Sosyal Sınıflar Üzerine" /><published>2019-06-25T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-06-25T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/25/martin-eden</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/25/martin-eden.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/martin-eden/martin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lecturer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack London. Uzun zamandır beni en çok etkileyen kitaplardan biri olan Martin Eden’in yazarı büyük üstad. Yaşadığı hayat hakkında bilgi edindikten sonra ayrı bir saygı duydum kendisine. Size de tanıtmak amaçlı çok kısa ondan bahsetmek istiyorum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack London yani gerçek adıyla John Griffith London, 1876 yılında San Francisco’da doğdu. Çocukluğu alabildiğine hareketli geçen ustanın en büyük zevki kitap okumaktı, ancak ailesinin güç koşullarda yaşaması yüzünden on dört yaşında okulu bırakıp bir konserve fabrikasında çalışmaya başladı. On altı yaşına geldiğinde San Francisco Körfezi’nde sokak çetelerine katılmanın yanı sıra, kıyı devriyesi olarak da görev yapmış biriydi. 1893’te, hem para kazanmak hem de maceraperest duygularını tatmin için fok avına çıkan bir gemiyle Japonya’ya kadar gitti. ABD’ye döndükten sonra da tüm ülkeyi baştan başa dolaştı. Ancak kitaplara ve okumaya adeta aşkla bağlıydı. İçinde ukte kalan eğitimine devam etmek için yoğun çalışmaların ardından California Üniversitesi’ne girmeyi başardı, fakat yine maddi zorluklar sebebiyle kısa sürede ayrılmak zorunda kaldı. 1897’de, Klondike’ta altın madeni bulunduğu haberi üzerine altın aramaya koyuldu. 1900’de öykülerinden oluşan ve ülke çapında tanınmasını sağlayan “The Son of the Wolf” adlı kitabı yayınladı. 1902’de Londra’ya gidip kenar mahallelerde yaşayan insanların hayatlarını inceleyen London’ın hayatı olaylar ve maceralarla doluydu. Güney denizlerinde dolaştı, Rus-Japon Savaşı’nda muhabirlik yaptı. Tüm bu yaşadığı olaylar ve edindiği deneyimler eserlerinin zeminini oluşturdu. 1916’da ise erken sayılabilecek bir yaşta California’da intihar ederek bu hayattan ayrıldı.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin Eden kitabı ise bana göre Jack London’ın en değerli eseri sayılabilecek ve kendi yaşantısından çok sayıda izler taşıyan bir otobiyografik romandır. London bu romanında burjuva gerçekliği karşısında sınıf atlamak isteyen genç bir yazar olan Martin Eden isimli bir roman kahramanının düştüğü trajik durumu harika bir şekilde resmetmiştir. London sanki bu romanında tüm düşüncelerini, söylediklerini, söylemek isteyip de söyleyemediklerini, insanlardan ve rezil dünya düzeninden nefretini Martin Eden karakteriyle anlatmak istemiştir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canım ailem zamanında bana hiç hissettirmemeye çalışsa da görece yoksul bir çocukluk geçirmiştim. İyi ki de öyle olmuş. Sonrasında da aldığım eğitimle o meşhur toplum basamaklarını çıkmaya başladım. Kendimi mümkün olduğunca geliştirmeye çalıştım. Mezuniyetime birkaç ay kalmıştı. O sıralar yarı zamanlı olarak meşhur beyaz yakalı kesimin arasında çalışıyordum. Zaten mezuniyete kadar birçok kez sorguladığım hayattaki kararlarımı tekrar sorgulamaya başlamıştım. Tam işte öyle bir dönemde Martin Eden’i okumuştum. Belki de böyle bir döneme denk geldiği için beni bu kadar etkiledi, bilemiyorum. Hala da şaşkınım aslında biraz. Benden 100 yıl önce yaşamış bir insanla benzer durumları yaşayıp benzer duyguları hissetmiştik. Kitapların gücüne bir kez daha inandım ve de bu dünyanın düzeninin kolay kolay değişmeyeceğine. Aradan 100 yıl geçmesine rağmen hala hiçbir gelişme olmamış gibi. Kendi hislerimi ve daha da fazlasını kitaptan alıntıladığım Jack London’ın sözleriyle daha iyi açıklarım sanıyorum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Elbette ne söylersem söyleyeyim saygı ve dikkatle dinliyorsunuz. Sizler çürümüş, haksız kazanç sağlayan insanlarsınız desem öfkeleneceğinize kem küm eder, söylediklerimde büyük bir doğruluk payı olduğunu kabul edersiniz. Peki neden? Ünlü olduğum için, çok param olduğu için. Martin Eden olduğum için değil, fena bir herif olmayan, hiç de aptal sayılamayacak Martin Eden olduğum için değil. Size kalkıp ayın yeşil peynirden yapıldığını söylesem hemen kalkıp bu görüşü benimsersiniz, ya da en azından karşı çıkmazsınız. Çünkü param var benim, hem de dağ gibi. Halbuki bunlar çok önceden kazanılmış şeylerdi; bana ayağınızın kiriymişim gibi davranıp üstüme tükürdüğünüz sırada bu işler bitmişti.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Kendisini çok yaşlı hissediyordu, eski günlerinin şu kayıtsız, gamsız genç yoldaşlarından yüzyıllarca daha yaşlı. Çok fazla, geri dönemeyecak kadar fazla uzaklaşmıştı onlardan. Onların, bir zamanlar kendisinin de katıldığı yaşam biçimi çok tatsız geliyordu şimdi. Düşkırıklığına uğramıştı. Bir yabancıya dönüşmüştü artık. Ucuz bira nasıl tatsız geldiyse bu insanların arkadaşlıkları da yavan geliyordu ona. Onların çok önlerindeydi. Aralarında bilmem kaç kitap açılmış duruyordu. Kendisini sürgüne göndermiş, engin bir bilgi dünyasında, bir daha yuvasına geri dönemeyecak kadar dolaşmıştı.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;” ‘Ne olmuş Amerika Birleşik Devletleri’ne?’ diye karşılık verdi Martin. ‘On üç koloni, yöneticilerini devirip Cumhuriyet dedikleri yönetimi kurdular. Köleler kendi kendilerinin efendisi oldu. Artık kılıçlı efendiler yoktu. Fakat, ne olursanız olun efendisiz kalamazsınız, bu yüzden yeni bir efendi tipi türedi. Bu seferkiler büyük, güçlü, soylu efendiler değil; örümcek gibi her şeyi saran, hileci tüccarlar ve tefecilerdi. Bunlar sizi yeniden köleleştirdi, ne var ki, gerçek, soylu efendinin kol kuvvetiyle yapacağı gibi mertçe ve açıkça değil; gizlice, örümcek gibi ağlar örerek, yaltaklanarak, tatlı dille yalanlar dökerek yaptılar. Bunlar sizin köle yargıçlarınızı satın aldılar, köle yasalarınızı bozdular, dahası sizin köle kızlarınızı ve oğullarınızı köle mülkiyetindekinden de beter bir dehşete sürüklediler. İki milyon çocuğunuz bugün, Amerika Birleşik Devletleri’nin ticaret oligarşisinin emrinde çalışıyor. Sizin gibi on milyon kölenin ne karnı doyuyor, ne de başını sokacak doğru düzgün bir yeri var.’ “&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Düşünüyorum da, saflık zamanlarımda, güzel evlerde oturan, öğrenim görmüş, bankalarda hesapları olan, yüksek tabakadan bu insanların bir şey olduğunu sanırdım.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;-“Ben bir Cumhuriyetçiyim” diyerek yumuşak bir şekilde araya girdi bay Morse. “Beni hangi sınıfa sokuyorsunuz?”
-“Ah, siz bilinçsiz bir uşaksınız.”
-“Uşak mı?”
-“Elbette, bir şirket için çalışıyorsunuz. Ne işçi sınıfındansınız ne de herhangi bir sabıkanız var. Gelirinizi, karısını dövenler ya da yankesiciler üzerinden kazanmıyorsunuz. Geçiminizi toplumun efendilerinden sağlıyorsunuz, bir insanı besleyen de o adamın efendisidir. Evet, siz bir uşaksınız. Sizi, hizmet ettiğiniz sermayenin çıkarlarını geliştirmek ilgilendirir.”
…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Bugüne kadar sürekli bir yer bulamamıştı kendine. Bulunduğu her yere ayak uydurmuş, çalışırken de oyun oynarken de sağlam durduğu, haklarını elde etmek ve saygı görmek için mücadelede kararlı ve usta olduğu için, her zaman ve her yerde gözde olmuştu. Ama hiçbir yerde kök salamamıştı. Kendini değil de çevresini tatmin etmek için yeterince uyum göstermişti. İçi her zaman bir rahatsızlık duygusuyla altüst olmuş, kulağı her zaman öteden gelen çağrıyı işitmiş, bütün hayatı kitapları, aşkı ve sanatı keşfedene kadar aramak ve dolaşmakla geçmişti.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Yoksulluğun hiç de sevimli bir şey olmadığını bilmekle birlikte, onda da yoksulluğun, onurunu ve ümidini kaybetmemiş herkesi başarıya doğru iten sivri bir mahmuz ve dolayısıyla sağlıklı bir şey olduğu yolundaki, o rahat orta sınıf inanışı vardı.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Ama ben benim. Kendi beğenimin, çoğunluğun beğenisine boyun eğmesine izin veremem. Eğer bir şeyden hoşlanmıyorsam ondan hoşlanmıyorumdur, hepsu bu; ve çoğunluk hoşlanıyor ya da hoşlandığını sanıyor diye, hoşlanıyormuş gibi yapmam için de tek bir neden yok. Hoşlandığım ve hoşlanmadığım şeyler konusunda modaya uymam.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Bir konunun üzerinde kuluçkaya yatıp onu iyice olgunlaştırdıktan sonra, hemen daktilo başına geçmeyi adet edinmişti. Yazının yayınlanmaması onu çok fazla rahatsız etmiyordu. Yazmak, dağınık düşünce dizilerini bir araya getirerek ve zihne yüklenen tüm verileri nihai bir genellemeye tabi tutarak yapılan uzun bir zihinsel sürecin doruk noktasıydı. Böyle bir makale yazmak, Martin’in zihninde yeni sorunlar ve malzemelere yer açmak amacıyla gerçekleştirdiği bilinçli bir çabaydı. Bu, bir bakıma, gerçek ya da hayali dertlerden bunalan ve sabırlı sessizliklerini zaman zaman bozup ‘diyeceklerini demeden’ susmayan insanların bildik alışkanlığına benziyordu.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Ama Rut’a duyduğu aşk, güzelliğe duyduğu aşkın da ötesindeydi. Aşkın dünyadaki en güzel şey olduğuna inanıyordu. Onda devrim yapan, onu kaba saba bir denizciden bir öğrenciye ve sanatçıya dönüştüren şey aşktı; bu yüzden aşk, ona göre, bilim-sanat-aşk üçgeninin en önde geleniydi.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her insanın başka bir insandan öğreneceği bir şeyler olduğunan inanan ben kendi elimizle yarattığımız bu sosyal normlardan ve sınıflardan toplum olarak kurtulacağımız günü iple çekiyorum, her ne kadar pek umutlu olmasam da. Buralara kadar okuyan olur mu bilmiyorum ama gelen kişiye de bir &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ituzi_-9RJI&quot;&gt;şarkı&lt;/a&gt; bırakayım madem. Sevgiyle kalın…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/martin-eden/martin.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My Observations about Being a Good/Bad Lecturer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/22/lecturer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Observations about Being a Good/Bad Lecturer" /><published>2019-06-22T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-06-22T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/22/lecturer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/22/lecturer.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/lecturer/college-lecture.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lecturer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I would like to share my observations about lecturers I encountered throughout my undergraduate life in Electrical and Electronics Engineering. Although, I really enjoy being an engineer and I chose my field on purpose, there were only few lecturers whose teaching style is really good. I am especially thankful to &lt;strong&gt;Prof. Umut Orguner&lt;/strong&gt; and his perfect teaching style. I hope I can be as good as him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, here are some effective and useful methods my professors use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the lectures (like 5-10 minutes), reminding what we did in the last lecture and then smoothly switching to that day’s lecture. In this way, even if I couldn’t revise previous lecture, I can still understand that day’s lecture clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Asking students whether they have any questions regarding the content by pausing intentionally between different parts of the lecture.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Of course, having a readable handwriting :)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Explaining the lecture in a simple way and without assuming students already know it. For example, while studying state space representation, reminding how to take 3x3 matrices inverse instead of saying “You have already learnt this!”.
If the part that students need to remember is too long, providing enough extra study material like handsheet for students to remember.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Providing an overall picture of the course content and connecting different subjects of the lecture smoothly. It is important to know name of the concept/method/problem you are studying.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If possible, giving a real life example regarding the content. Even if real life problem is much more complicated, knowing physical correspondence helps better understanding and motivates students.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Being honest to students. Instead of pretending to know everything, admitting you don’t know that particular thing and willing to learn more for the next lecture (if it is related).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sharing some funny and informative videos regarding lecture (if possible) at the last part of the lecture. We all know that last minutes of the lecture might be boring. In this way, I believe both students and lecturer be happy. During the time that I was taking an &lt;strong&gt;Electromechanical Energy Conversion&lt;/strong&gt; course, our lecturer shows us videos related to course content like magnets, dc motors, electric motor etc. at the of the lecture. I remember how much I enjoy during that time. Our lecturer name is &lt;strong&gt;Mr. Ozan Keysan&lt;/strong&gt;. He is also a great lecturer. &lt;a href=&quot;http://keysan.me/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is his blog address.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Providing problem sets with solutions to help students apprehend the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sharing previous years exams to give an idea about structure of the exam.
I believe even one example is enough.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Giving challenging homeworks, but asking easy questions in the exam. In my opinion, this is really a good strategy since you learn the subject quite well thanks to homeworks, and thanks to relatively easy exams, you don’t concern about grades and only focus to learn. I am grateful to &lt;strong&gt;Mr. Mert Ankarali&lt;/strong&gt; for this. You can visit his blog using &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.metu.edu.tr/mertan/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I personally prefer traditional classroom style where lecturer uses blackboard and students take notes. However, sometimes it is necessary to use some visualization to not waste too much time for drawing to board. For this style, providing lecture notes with some intentional blanks for students to fill works very well. For example, in &lt;strong&gt;Signal and Systems&lt;/strong&gt; course, we had printed lecture notes whose 70% was already filled, but some parts were empty like answers of the examples and some warnings. Lecturer also used the same lecture notes and as students we were only writing necessary parts. In this way, we can follow the lecture easily, and we have wonderful and complete lecture notes. For me, this method is quite beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Preparing lecture content weekly as well to have comprehensive knowledge of subjects and adjusting lecture time perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sharing anonymous questionnaires about course to get feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, good lecturers I encountered can be counted on the fingers of one hand. Most of the time, I face with really bad lecturers. Either they really know the subject, but suck at teaching or they don’t care teaching at all. Of course, we can still learn from them what we shouldn’t do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some common characteristics of bad lecturers I have seen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using the same voice tone throughout the lecture, which makes students sleepy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Following &lt;strong&gt;Powerpoint Slides&lt;/strong&gt; blindly i.e. only reading what is written in slides.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wasting too much time on unimportant things in the lecture. For example, stucking at unnecessary and unrelated student questions and spending too much time to answer them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Deeply explaining concepts that are already covered by other lectures. I can give an example to describe this point. In one course spending two weeks to explain linearization procedure (which is just a step for that course) while in the same semester there is another course that we have already learnt linearization procedure deeply and very well. Instead, lecturer should shortly remind it in 10-20 minutes. It is important to analyze the curriculum and be aware of what and how much students know.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Related to previous point, not following other courses of students in same semester and pretending that your course is the only course that students are dealing with. This causes to having extremely heavy workload in specific weeks and reduces motivation of students. Believe me, as students we always appreciate professors who are aware of our situation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pretending to know everything related to course and not giving students a chance to ask questions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Making fun of students’ questions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Preparing exams that are almost not related at all what is studied in classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This point happens especially for laboratory courses. Teaching simple stuff in lab hours and requiring extremely difficult lab projects from students to complete. I am aware of the fact that university is a place for students to make research and learn by themselves, but still keeping everything to students doesn’t make sense at all. I remember that in our digital electronics laboratory, we studied simple hello world or if-else structure in verilog language, but image recognition algorithm was given as a term project which should be implemented in FPGA using Verilog. That was the first time we programmed FPGA and thanks to this project I literally hated electronics courses.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, all these points are relative. Maybe other students disagree with me, but anyway, I wanted to share my observations to not forget what I went through in my undergraduate life. Hopefully, I will not do the things I don’t like when I was student.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/lecturer/college-lecture.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">TransferWise: Send Money Abroad at Lowest Possible Cost</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/14/transferwise.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TransferWise: Send Money Abroad at Lowest Possible Cost" /><published>2019-06-14T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-06-14T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/14/transferwise</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/14/transferwise.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/transferwise/tw.webp&quot; alt=&quot;TransferWise&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TransferWise&lt;/strong&gt; is a UK-based money transfer service which allows its users to transfer money internationally at lowest possible transfer fee. It achieves this by using two local transfers instead of one international transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you want to send money to USA from UK. You can easily achieve this using TransferWise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First you need to sign up a new TransferWise account via &lt;a href=&quot;https://transferwise.com/&quot;&gt;TransferWise website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Website is quite easy to catch. Follow the steps named &lt;strong&gt;Send Money&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Enter the amount that you want to send. In this case, you will use your pound account in UK, so you will be converting pound to dolar. For example, you want to send 500$ to a friend in USA. As you can see in the below picture, for this you need to send 397.13£ and transfer fee is only 2.22£.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/transferwise/tw3.png&quot; alt=&quot;TransferWise 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After that you can click &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;. You will need to enter all details related to the bank account you want to send the money.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Transaction&lt;/strong&gt; step, system will give you a local &lt;strong&gt;IBAN&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Transaction Number&lt;/strong&gt; that you are going to transfer the money in. In this way, you are actually going to make a local transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After this step, all you need to do is wait. System will send you an e-mail that confirms that they receive your money. After that you are gonna get another e-mail that confirms that your money is arrived to USA.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a simple diagram that shows how system works:
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/transferwise/tw2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TransferWise 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to worry about the safety of the system. I personally used it and it works perfect. You can further search Google for user comments about TransferWise. Thanks to TransferWise, you don’t need to pay 45$ transaction fee for a 500$ transfer :) Boo &lt;strong&gt;Western Union&lt;/strong&gt;!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/transferwise/tw.webp" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Berlin Living &amp;amp; Travel Guide</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/02/berlin-guide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Berlin Living &amp; Travel Guide" /><published>2019-06-02T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-06-02T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/02/berlin-guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/06/02/berlin-guide.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/reichstag.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reichstag&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I will try to give all necessary tips about living in Berlin, and I will also provide an awesome travel guide for you to discover the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;accommodation--transportation&quot;&gt;Accommodation &amp;amp; Transportation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are coming to Berlin as a tourist, accommodation won’t cause any problem for you. There are many hotels or hostels in the Berlin.  Unfortunately, I won’t be able to give specific hostel/hotel names. I stayed at &lt;strong&gt;Pegasus Hostel Berlin&lt;/strong&gt; (near to Berlin Ostbahnhof) during my first visit to Berlin as a tourist, and it was okay. I can say that staying in a hotel which is close to city center would be beneficial for you. For this purpose, you may want to stay in &lt;strong&gt;Mitte&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Kreuzberg&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Schöneberg&lt;/strong&gt; districts of Berlin. Nonetheless, if you stay another district, that’s okay as well since public transportation is quite advanced in Berlin and you can go anywhere you like using public transportation. During weekends, &lt;strong&gt;SBahns&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Ubahns&lt;/strong&gt; works all day including night. During weekdays, they are closed after some time at night, but there are &lt;strong&gt;Night Buses&lt;/strong&gt; in the same routes. By the way, I should mention that &lt;strong&gt;Buses&lt;/strong&gt; always work 24 hour. Hence, transportation in Berlin never disappoints you. There are no ticket barriers in metro. You should buy appropriate ticket for you. Officers perform ticket check during the week at random times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/districts.png&quot; alt=&quot;Berlin Districts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For navigation, I prefer to use &lt;strong&gt;Google Maps&lt;/strong&gt;. I definitely suggest it for you. You can see all possible routes in real time. Trust me, you are going to need this, since there are many SBahn, UBahn and Bus routes. It is quite easy to get lost, especially in first days :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/google-maps.png&quot; alt=&quot;Berlin Districts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;supermarkets&quot;&gt;Supermarkets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many different supermarkets in Berlin. &lt;strong&gt;Aldi&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Lidl&lt;/strong&gt; are the cheapest ones. &lt;strong&gt;Edeka&lt;/strong&gt; could be an alternative option as well. Of course, generally the closest market to your house is always the best, but they might be small like &lt;strong&gt;Penny&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Netto&lt;/strong&gt;. For bigger supermarkets, you can check &lt;strong&gt;Rewe&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Kaufland&lt;/strong&gt;. However, as I mentioned, they don’t have too many branch like others. If you are looking for Turkish supermarkets, &lt;strong&gt;Eurogida&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Bolu&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Nazar&lt;/strong&gt; etc. would be a perfect option. You can get more information about supermarkets visiting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archer-relocation.com/a-complete-guide-to-supermarkets-in-berlin/&quot;&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Germans are not very used to have quite big shopping malls like us, so if you are looking for someplace like that, you could be dissappointed. As far as I know, &lt;strong&gt;Kaufhaus Des Westens a.k.a. Kadewe&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Bikini Berlin&lt;/strong&gt; are the only shopping malls in Berlin. I personally don’t recommend to visit for shopping since the prices are unnecessarily expensive. You can visit for touristic purposes, and I will mention it in the following sections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/kadewe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kadewe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost all supermarkets are closed on Sunday like every country in Europe, so be aware of that and get prepared. There are some places called &lt;strong&gt;Spätkauf&lt;/strong&gt; to buy simple stuff. You can also use them in late night. As you expect, they are more expensive than normal supermarkets, but not too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/spatkauf.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Spatkauf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also visit traditional &lt;strong&gt;flea markets&lt;/strong&gt;. They are like bazaars and set up in public parks. You can discover incredible things with incredible prices. If you are looking for some souivenirs for your lovings, flea markets would be perfect place for you. You can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visitberlin.de/en/blog/top-11-berlin-flea-markets&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about flea markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/fleamarket.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flea Market&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this section, I can talk about &lt;strong&gt;recyling&lt;/strong&gt; lastly. In Germany, you need to seperate your trash properly for recyling like every coutry. Of course, the seperations differ from country to country, but it is not going to be problem for you. The thing which is different is the term &lt;strong&gt;Pfand&lt;/strong&gt;. Whenever, you buy something to drink, you will see that there is an extra fee called &lt;strong&gt;Pfand&lt;/strong&gt;. It means refundable. You can return these items to the places called &lt;strong&gt;Pfand Station&lt;/strong&gt;, you can get your money back. You can find these stations mostly in bigger supermarkets. Moreover, when you are at outside, don’t surprise if you see somebody picking up all the &lt;strong&gt;pfand-able&lt;/strong&gt; bottles around. Some people earn their money using this way. In short, it is good for both environment and your pocket. You can follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archer-relocation.com/how-to-recycle-in-germany/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to get more information about recyling in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/pfand-station.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Pfand Station&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mobile-operators-and-internet&quot;&gt;Mobile Operators and Internet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are going to stay in Germany for a short time, it is wise to buy a prepaid simcard rather than making contract. There are many different prepaid simcard options with different mobile operators. When I was in Berlin, I used &lt;strong&gt;Ayyildiz&lt;/strong&gt; mobile operator with an offering 15 GB Internet per month for 15€. It was more than enough for me. You can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://budgettraveller.org/travelling-to-germany-tips-for-getting-mobile-internet-access/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to learn more. If you are going to stay longer, you might want to make a contract. Please follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.movingto-berlin.com/mobile-contract/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to see a comparison between different mobile operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; One good thing about Berlin is that there is &lt;strong&gt;Free Wifi&lt;/strong&gt; in Ubahn stations and it is quite fast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Internet usage (both mobile or home), you need to be careful. You shouldn’t use Torrent or IPTV or you shouldn’t make illegal downloadings. Germany is quite strict about illegal downloadings. If you get caught, you might have to pay a fine (more than 1000€), so please be careful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discover-the-city&quot;&gt;Discover the City&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-&quot;&gt;1-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you should do to learn more about the City is attending a tour. You can attend &lt;strong&gt;SANDEMANs Free Tour of Berlin&lt;/strong&gt; which takes 3 hour. If you like it, you can take other paid tours as well. You can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neweuropetours.eu/sandemans-tours/berlin/free-tour-of-berlin/&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt; to learn tour dates and hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tour starts from &lt;strong&gt;Starbucks at Brandenburg Gate&lt;/strong&gt;. Look out people with &lt;strong&gt;Red Umbrella&lt;/strong&gt;, they are the guides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/brandenburg-gate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Brandenburg Gate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tour route may vary from guide to guide, but you will see the main tourist attractions like &lt;strong&gt;Memorial to the Murdered Jews of Europe (Holocaust Memorial)&lt;/strong&gt;,  &lt;strong&gt;Some Parts of Berlin Wall&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Checkpoint Charlie&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Gendarmenmarkt&lt;/strong&gt;. The tour will end at &lt;strong&gt;Bebelplatz&lt;/strong&gt;. This tour is really a good way to make a quick start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/holocaust-memorial.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Holocaust Memorial&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/checkpoint-charlie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Checkpoint Charlie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/gendarmenmarkt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gendarmenmarkt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/bebelplatz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bebelplatz&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-&quot;&gt;2-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can visit &lt;strong&gt;Mauerpark&lt;/strong&gt; on Sundays. There are karaoke, street performance and lots of fun. It is definitely a great way to spend a lovely Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/mauerpark.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mauerpark 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/mauerpark2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Mauerpark 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/mauerpark3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Mauerpark 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-&quot;&gt;3-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;strong&gt;Klunkerkranich&lt;/strong&gt; to watch the sunset over the rooftops of Berlin. It is a rooftop bar with a fantastic view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/klunkerkranich.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Klunkerkranich&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-&quot;&gt;4-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;strong&gt;Kaiser Wilhelm Memorial Church&lt;/strong&gt; which is damaged during the World War 2. You can enjoy the view from the terrace of &lt;strong&gt;Motel One&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Monkey Bar&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;NENI BERLIN&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/kaiserwilhelm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kaiser Wilhelm Memorial Church&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-&quot;&gt;5-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;strong&gt;East Side Gallery&lt;/strong&gt;: the longest air gallery in the world. Take a long walk along the East Side Gallery to learn the history of Berlin Wall and see amazing art work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/east-side-gallery.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;East Side Gallery&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that you can use beautiful &lt;strong&gt;Oberbaum Bridge&lt;/strong&gt; to cross the river. This bridge will provide you amazing background for a new profile picture :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/oberbraum-bridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Oberbaum Bridge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a hamburger restaurant named &lt;strong&gt;Burgermeister&lt;/strong&gt; at the end of Oberbaum Bridge. Their hamburgers and fries are delicious, but I should warn you about long waiting line. They have another shop in Kreuzberg. There is generally less people there, so you won’t need a lot. Nonetheless, I prefer this one because while eating your hamburger, you can enjoy the amazing view of &lt;strong&gt;East Side Gallery&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Oberbaum Bridge&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/burger-meister.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Burgermeister&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/burgermeister-view.png&quot; alt=&quot;Burgermeister View&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-&quot;&gt;6-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;strong&gt;Kruezberg Canal (Landwehr Canal/Urbanhafen)&lt;/strong&gt; and embrace the nature. Great place to take your drink and socialize with your friends. You can also visit &lt;strong&gt;Admiral Bridge&lt;/strong&gt; in the same area. It offers great atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/landwehr1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Kreuzberg Canal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/landwehr2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Kreuzberg Canal 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/admiral-bridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Admiral Bridge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/landwehr3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Kreuzberg Canal 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-&quot;&gt;7-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berlin offers various cafes, pubs, clubs. Here are some near &lt;strong&gt;Görlitzer Park&lt;/strong&gt;. However, you should be careful and stay away from the park itself. Generally the park is unfortunately known for drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birgit &amp;amp; Beer&lt;/strong&gt; is a beer garden with exotic ambience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/birgitandbeer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Birgit &amp;amp; Beer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das Edelweiss&lt;/strong&gt; holds great jazz sessions.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/dasedelweiss.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Das Edelweiss&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;800px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mano Cafe&lt;/strong&gt; is a cosy place with vintage aura and enough space for small crowds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/manocafe.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mano Cafe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bite Club&lt;/strong&gt; holds an open-air food festival in summer months. You should visit if you like street food. Check &lt;a href=&quot;http://biteclub.de/&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/biteclub.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bite Club&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Club der Visionaere&lt;/strong&gt; is a riverside bar with electronic music and parties at nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/clubdervisionere.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Club der Visionaere&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-&quot;&gt;8-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Viktoriapark&lt;/strong&gt; is a great public park with waterfalls and viewpoints to relax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/viktoriapark.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Viktoriapark&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-&quot;&gt;9-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schlachtensee&lt;/strong&gt; is always a good idea to run away from the city. If you go summer, you will see that a lot of people swim in this lake. If you like biking, visiting this lake by bike would be perfect for you. If you feel a bit lazy, you can take your bike with you to SBahn/Ubahn and use your bike only to discover the lake. However, check that your train ticket involves the right to carry bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/schlachtensee.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Schlachtensee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/schlachtensee2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Schlachtensee 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-&quot;&gt;10-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hackesche Höfe&lt;/strong&gt; is composed of historical small and sweet courtyards. After that you can taste rose shaped delicicious ice-creams of &lt;strong&gt;Amorino&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/hackeschehofe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hackesche Höfe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/hackeschehofe2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Hackesche Höfe 2&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/hackeschehofe3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Amorino Icecreams&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;11-&quot;&gt;11-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if they are expensive, it is still delightful to visit shopping malls &lt;strong&gt;KaDeWe&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Bikini Berlin&lt;/strong&gt;. I personally like foodhall and suparmarket part of KaDeWe. Shops in Bikini Berlin are also charming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/bikiniberlin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bikini Berlin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/kadewe2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;KaDeWe Food Hall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;12-&quot;&gt;12-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a small church named &lt;strong&gt;Nikolaikirche&lt;/strong&gt;. Behind this course, there exists a small area named &lt;strong&gt;Nikolaiviertel&lt;/strong&gt;. I really like narrow paths in this area with humble cafes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/nikolaiviertel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nikolaiviertel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/nikolaiviertel2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nikolaiviertel 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/nikolaiviertel3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nikolaiviertel 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/nikolaiviertel4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nikolaiviertel 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;13-&quot;&gt;13-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clärchens Ballroom&lt;/strong&gt; could be a satisfactory choice for people who are looking for a classy German restaurant with live music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/clarchens.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Clärchens Ballroom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;14-&quot;&gt;14-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kastanienallee&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the hit regions of Berliners. You can find lots of cafe, restaurant throughout this region. It also provides great street views with fascinating architectures. Whether you are with your friend or alone, it is always a good idea to go for a walk in this region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/kastanialle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kastanienallee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/kastanialle2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kastanienallee 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/kastanialle3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Kastanienallee 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/kastanialle4.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Kastanienallee 4&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;15-&quot;&gt;15-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can visit &lt;strong&gt;Drachenberg&lt;/strong&gt; which offers a fantactic top-view of the City. After that you can go and visit &lt;strong&gt;Teufelsberg Spy Towers&lt;/strong&gt; which was a listening station during the Cold War.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/teufelsberg.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Drachenberg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/teufelsberg2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Drachenberg 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/teufelsberg3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Teufelsberg Spy Towers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/teufelsberg4.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Teufelsberg Spy Towers 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/teufelsberg5.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Teufelsberg Spy Towers 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;16-&quot;&gt;16-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germany Parliament Building &lt;strong&gt;Reichstag&lt;/strong&gt;, which is still actively used, must be seen. If you book in advance (like 2-3 week before), you can visit characteristic glass dome &lt;strong&gt;Reichstag Dome&lt;/strong&gt; for free. It is the only place in Reichstag that Hitler never stepped foot in. You can also get quite informative audio guide for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/reichstag.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reichstag&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/reichstagdome.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reichstag Dome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/reichstagdome.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Reichstag Dome 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;17-&quot;&gt;17-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holzmarkt&lt;/strong&gt; is an excellent place near the river which has very exotic pubs and cafes. I like the bar &lt;strong&gt;Holzmarkt Pampa&lt;/strong&gt;’s atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/holzmarkt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Holzmarkt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/holzmarkt2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Holzmarkt 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/holzmarkt3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Holzmarkt 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;18-&quot;&gt;18-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can visit rococo style &lt;strong&gt;Charlottenburg Palace&lt;/strong&gt; and its huge garden. Although there is an entrance fee for palace, beautiful garden can be discovered for free. Moreover, you can also visit all the palace for free in the last Sunday of each month. There is no nearby market to the Palace, so it is highly recommended that take your snacks and drinks with you before coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/charlottenburg.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Charlottenburg Palace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/charlottenburg2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Charlottenburg Palace 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;19-&quot;&gt;19-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cafe am Engelbecken&lt;/strong&gt; is lovely, cosy and calming cafe which is located near a small lake. The prices are not too expensive especially if you think about its location. It might be a perfect place to read your book while enjoying your coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/engelbecken2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cafe am Engelbecken&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/engelbecken.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cafe am Engelbecken 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;20-&quot;&gt;20-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a boat ride, instead of paying money for touristic cruise tours, you can use &lt;strong&gt;BVG’s Ferry&lt;/strong&gt; with your BVG ticket that you use in SBahns, UBahns and buses. There is a great route for this purpose. You can go &lt;strong&gt;Wansee&lt;/strong&gt; using SBahn and then you can walk just 2 minutes to &lt;strong&gt;Wansee Station&lt;/strong&gt;. Take &lt;strong&gt;BVG F10 Ferry&lt;/strong&gt; which goes to &lt;strong&gt;Station Kladow&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Kladow&lt;/strong&gt; will welcome you with a great view and lovely cafes. After getting some snacks and drinks from supermarkets near Kladow Station, you can follow &lt;strong&gt;Imchenallee&lt;/strong&gt; street throughout river. If you are willing to go further, you deserve to enjoy a nice coffee in &lt;strong&gt;Sommercafé im Landhausgarten Dr. Max Fraenkel&lt;/strong&gt;. You can either walk or get on a bicycle, but if you are on foot, then it is better to return to Station Kladow by taking bus from the nearest bus stop &lt;strong&gt;Hottengrund&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t forget to check the last take off time of the ferrys from Station Kladow to Station Wansee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/wansee.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Station Wansee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/wansee4.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Station Wansee 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/wansee2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Station Kladow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/wansee3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Station Kladow 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/wansee5.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Imchenallee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/wansee6.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Imchenallee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After returning Station Wansee, you can appreciate pleasing evening with sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/sunset.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset at Wansee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/sunset2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset at Wansee 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;21-&quot;&gt;21-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treptower Park&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the biggest public parks in Berlin. In the middle of the park, there is &lt;strong&gt;Soviet War Memorial&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a cemetery for Soviet Soldiers in WW2. You can take pedal boats from here. There is a nearby &lt;strong&gt;Burger King&lt;/strong&gt; which offers great view of the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/treptow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Treptower Park&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/treptow2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Treptower Park 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/treptow3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Treptower Park 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/treptow4.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Treptower Park 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;22-&quot;&gt;22-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill your stomach with yummy street food in &lt;strong&gt;Markthalle Neun&lt;/strong&gt; on Thursdays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/markthalle.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Markthalle Neun&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/markthalle2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Markthalle Neun 2&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;23-&quot;&gt;23-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fastfood chain &lt;strong&gt;RISA&lt;/strong&gt; is like &lt;strong&gt;KFC&lt;/strong&gt;, but with better taste and cheaper price. Just try it and you are going to agree with me :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/risa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RISA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;24-&quot;&gt;24-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are extremely many museums in Berlin. Specify the ones that get your attention. No need to say that &lt;strong&gt;Museum Island&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Berliner Dome&lt;/strong&gt; must be seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Museum Island&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Berliner Dom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topography of Terror:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;ToT&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum4.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;ToT 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DDR Museum:&lt;/strong&gt; Interactive museum to learn about the life in East Germany before the fall of Berlin Wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/ddr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DDR&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tränenpalast:&lt;/strong&gt; This small free museum shows the tragedy that has happened in the border of East-West Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum5.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Tranenpalast&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medizinhistorisches Museum:&lt;/strong&gt; Provides a path through medical history over past 300 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum6.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;medizin&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum7.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;medizin 2&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jewish Museum:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum8.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;jewish&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum9.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;jewish 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural History Museum:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/naturalhistory.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;natural&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/naturalhistory2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;natural2&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an annual event called &lt;strong&gt;Long Night Museum&lt;/strong&gt;. During one day, almost all museums in Berlin is open during the night as well. You can visit them with only one ticket. There is also shuttles between major museums. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lange-nacht-der-museen.de/en/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the event link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;25-&quot;&gt;25-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Botanical Gardens&lt;/strong&gt; is worth to visit if you like the nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum9.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;botanical&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/museum10.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;botanical 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;26-&quot;&gt;26-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is impossible to not mention &lt;strong&gt;Tiergarten&lt;/strong&gt;, the biggest public park of the Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/tier.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tiergarten&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;27-&quot;&gt;27-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;strong&gt;Urban Nation Streetart Museum&lt;/strong&gt; near &lt;strong&gt;Nollendorfplatz&lt;/strong&gt;. You are going to see wonderful pieces even in the street of museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/urban.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;urban&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/urban2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;urban 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/urban3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;urban 3&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;28-&quot;&gt;28-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tempelhofer Feld&lt;/strong&gt; is a former airport which was built under Nazi regime. It is now a public park. It is definitely great place for bicyling, skating or flying a kite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/tempelhof.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Tempelhof&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/tempelhof2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Tempelhof2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;29-&quot;&gt;29-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sachsenhausen Concentration Camp&lt;/strong&gt; is the nearest concentration camp to Berlin. It is only one hour way and you can use Sbahn to arrive here. It must be seen to embrace humanity more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/nazicamp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nazi Camp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/nazicamp2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Nazi Camp 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/nazicamp3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Nazi Camp 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;30-&quot;&gt;30-)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ritter Sport&lt;/strong&gt; is a German chocolate brand. It offers many different types of chocolates. For me, it is the best for its price. You can find these chocolates in every supermarket. However, they have their own shop named &lt;strong&gt;Ritter Sport Bunte Schokowelt Berlin&lt;/strong&gt;. If you want to buy lots of chocolate, this shop is the right place. You can also design your own chocolate in here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/ritter2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ritter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/ritter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ritter 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bonus&quot;&gt;BONUS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berlin is a great city with so much to offer for every kind of people. There are always an event, festival, concert etc. Follow Facebook events related to Berlin and use &lt;strong&gt;MeetUp&lt;/strong&gt; application to socialize and find events according to your interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Event&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Event2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Event3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Event4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Event5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event4.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Event4.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Event7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/berlin-guide/event6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Event6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/berlin-guide/reichstag.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Get Canada Study Permit? (Kanada Öğrenci Vizesi Nasıl Alınır?)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/15/canada-studypermit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Get Canada Study Permit? (Kanada Öğrenci Vizesi Nasıl Alınır?)" /><published>2019-05-15T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-05-15T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/15/canada-studypermit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/15/canada-studypermit.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/canada-flag.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Canada Flag&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;general-information-and-required-documents&quot;&gt;General Information and Required Documents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are going to Canada for educational purposes like language school, undergraduate/graduate studies, and you are going to stay more than 6 months, then you need to take a &lt;strong&gt;Study Permit&lt;/strong&gt;. Of course, this depends on your home country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I am going to share my experience about getting Canada Study Permit. My hometown is &lt;strong&gt;Turkey&lt;/strong&gt;, so all information in here will be related to application from Turkey. Yet, general procedure is pretty much same. Only some documents might differ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/services/study-canada/study-permit.html&quot;&gt;Canada Immigration and Citizenship website&lt;/a&gt; as a main source. You should check it out for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, the school that you are accepted in Canada should be one of the designated learning institutions (DLI). According to the Canada Immigration and Citizenship website, a designated learning institution (DLI) is a school approved by a provincial or territorial government to host international students. You will need an acceptance letter from a DLI. Check whether your school is a DLI or not using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/services/study-canada/study-permit/prepare/designated-learning-institutions-list.html&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prepared my documents by taking reference &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/services/study-canada/study-permit/prepare/get-documents.html&quot;&gt;Canada Immigration and Citizenship website document list&lt;/a&gt;. Here are the necessary documents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proof of acceptance (Acceptance letter from a DLI)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Valid Passport and Old Passports (if you have)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One Digital Biometric Photo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proof of financial support:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A letter from the school giving you money. It should include the amount of funding you will get with tuition fee. (personally I had just one acceptance letter from the university. The funding amount is written on that, but Tuition isn’t)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My bank statements for the past 6 months&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sponsorship Letter from my father. &lt;a href=&quot;/static/canada-studypermit/sponsorship-template.docx&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the template to download. Change it according to your situation. I just provided it to give you a clue about its format.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My sponsor’s 6 month salary roll&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My sponsor’s bank statements (I didn’t provide)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;House Title Deed (if applicable)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Vehicle License (if applicable)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Letter of explanation: This is probably the most important document of yours. You need to clearly explain why you want to take study permit. You can attach any file you want to letter of explanation. Please don’t forget that this file is the only thing that gives you a chance to convince visa officer. It is stated as optional in the website, but I personally believe that it should be MUST! &lt;a href=&quot;/static/canada-studypermit/letter-of-explanation-template.docx&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the template to download. I attached below files to my letter of explanation:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Student Certificate&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;TOEFL Score&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;GRE Score&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Transcript&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Curriculum Vitae (CV)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Criminal Record (e-devlet)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Letter of Acceptance from Universities in other countries&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My previous passport&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My National ID (Turkey)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Minimum amount of money that you need to show for financial support is stated as Tuition + 10.000 CAD per year for one  student (Outside Quebec, 2019 Year). You should check Canada Immigration website above to see the required amount applicable for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; I personally didn’t provide any accommodation arrangement or flight tickets to get study permit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-apply&quot;&gt;How to Apply?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can apply for study permit in either &lt;strong&gt;online&lt;/strong&gt; or via &lt;strong&gt;VFS Global&lt;/strong&gt;. VFS Global is a legal intermediary establishment for Canada visa applications. Depending on your country, there might be another establishment rather than VFS Global.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I preferred to apply online since it is easy and you don’t have to give extra money to VFS Global. To apply online, first visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/services/application/account.html&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; link to create an account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sign Up Options&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two different sign up options: via &lt;strong&gt;Sign-in Partner&lt;/strong&gt; or via &lt;strong&gt;GCkey&lt;/strong&gt;. Sign-in Partner option is for the people who have a Canadian bank account. Use GCkey if you don’t have Canadian bank account or a partner bank account (which is probably your case if you are applying in Turkey).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;GCkey Sign Up&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During sign-up process, please be careful and provide necessary information correctly. Moreover, you need to create some security questions with answers for yourself. These questions and answers will be super important since you are going to use one of them at each time you enter the &lt;strong&gt;CiC&lt;/strong&gt; website. Therefore, don’t forget to take a note!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After signing in to your account, you need to create a new application. For this purpose, scroll down &lt;strong&gt;Start an Application&lt;/strong&gt; section and click &lt;strong&gt;Apply to come to Canada&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Start an Application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Visitor visa, study and/or work permit&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Study Permit Button&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you will need to fill out a survey to find out whether you are eligible to apply a study permit. This survey at the end creates a personalized document checklist for your account to upload necessary documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Application Survey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can save your answers and exit the survey anytime you want using &lt;strong&gt;Save and Exit Questionnaire&lt;/strong&gt; button at the bottom left. You can proceed next pages of survey using &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt; button at the bottom right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After completion of the survey, you should be able to see &lt;strong&gt;Documents to Submit&lt;/strong&gt; page like below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Documents to Submit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there are some other extra documents to upload:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application for Study Permit Made Outside of Canada (IMM1294)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Family Information (IMM5645)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Schedule 1 - Application for a Temporary Resident Visa Made Outside Canada (IMM5257)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download these documents by clicking document name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; You need to use new versions of &lt;strong&gt;Adobe Reader&lt;/strong&gt; to open and edit these documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; You need to upload &lt;strong&gt;Letter of Explanation&lt;/strong&gt; with its attachments to &lt;strong&gt;Client Information&lt;/strong&gt; part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After uploading all the documents, you will pay the visa application fee online and your application will be completed. When there is an update about your document, you will receive an email to check your &lt;strong&gt;CiC&lt;/strong&gt; account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To read the message, you need to enter your account and click &lt;strong&gt;Check Full Application Status&lt;/strong&gt; under &lt;strong&gt;Vie the applications you submitted&lt;/strong&gt; part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Check Full Applcation Status&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scrool down to &lt;strong&gt;Messages about your application&lt;/strong&gt; part and you will see the messages regarding your application. Click them to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/canada-studypermit/7.png&quot; alt=&quot;CiC Messages&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t been in Canada before, you may need to give &lt;strong&gt;Biometrics&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks to survey you have filled out, if you need to give biometrics, you are going to pay necessary &lt;strong&gt;Biometrics Fee&lt;/strong&gt; and after a few days (for ex, 1 day for my application) you will receive a message &lt;strong&gt;Biometrics Collection Letter&lt;/strong&gt; which requests biometrics of yours. You need to visit &lt;strong&gt;VFS Global&lt;/strong&gt; to give biometrics. All detailed information is covered in received &lt;strong&gt;Biometrics Collection Letter&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After giving Biometrics, there is nothing to do left. All you need to is to wait. I got my study permit at my first attempt and it took exactly &lt;strong&gt;1 Month&lt;/strong&gt;. I paid &lt;strong&gt;150 CaD Study Permit Fee&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;85 CaD Biometrics Fee&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for this post. I wish you can get your visa at the first time you applied. If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to use comment section below. Study permit application might seem a bit complicated at first, but trust me it is not. Start to prepare documents early and don’t spend money on Visa Consultancy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/canada-studypermit/canada-flag.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Terminator: A Linux Terminal Emulator with Multiple Terminals in One</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/21/ubuntu-terminator.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Terminator: A Linux Terminal Emulator with Multiple Terminals in One" /><published>2019-04-21T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-21T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/21/ubuntu-terminator</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/21/ubuntu-terminator.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/terminator/8.png&quot; alt=&quot;My Terminal with ROS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As linux users, we all suffer from the default linux terminal when we try to call multiple terminals. We open new terminal each time and after some time, it becomes quite difficult to navigate between terminals. I had suffered from this during the time where I was trying to learn &lt;strong&gt;Robot Operating System (ROS)&lt;/strong&gt; because you need to call each script of ROS from another terminal, and default linux terminal made me crazy. Thanks to my friend Jean Pierre, I discovered an amazing Linux Terminal Emulator &lt;strong&gt;Terminator&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty about &lt;strong&gt;Terminator&lt;/strong&gt; is that it provides the ability to create multiple terminals in just one window. IT also allows you to change other terminal properties such as fonts, fonts colours, background color etc. In this post, I will try to explain installation of Terminator in Linux and give some tips that I frequently use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ubuntu-Based Distributions
    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt-get install terminator
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fedore &amp;amp; Other Derivatives
    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ dnf install terminator
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. It is installed successfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;usage--tips&quot;&gt;Usage &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After installation, just call the terminal with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CTRL + ALT + T&lt;/code&gt; 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/terminator/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Initial Terminator Startup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right click to terminal and choose split-horizontally or vertically.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/terminator/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Split&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, now we have two terminals in one window. You can navigate between terminals using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ALT+Arrow Keys&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/terminator/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Multiple Terminals&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can further split terminals.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/terminator/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Further Split&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right click to &lt;strong&gt;Preferences&lt;/strong&gt;. You can customize your terminal as you wish.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/terminator/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Preferences&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you go &lt;strong&gt;Keybindings&lt;/strong&gt; tab, you will see that there is a keyboard shortcut for almost every operation. I prefer to use default shortcuts, but you can change if you want. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/terminator/6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Keyboard Shortcuts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some shortcuts that I use commonly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ctrl + Shift + O  –&amp;gt; Split Horizontally&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ctrl + Shift + E  –&amp;gt; Split Vertically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ctrl + Shift + W  –&amp;gt; Close the Selected Terminal Window&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alt + Arrow Keys –&amp;gt; Navigate Between Terminal Windows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ctrl + Shift + X –&amp;gt; (De)Maximise the Selected Terminal Window&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alt + A –&amp;gt; Select all Terminals (For example, very useful when you try to connect using ssh and you need more terminals)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alt + G –&amp;gt; Deselect all Terminals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My terminal looks like below while I am working with ROS.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/terminator/7.png&quot; alt=&quot;My Terminal with ROS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for this post. I wish it would be useful :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/terminator/8.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Free Online Courses (Especially for ECE, CS and ME Students)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/10/best-onlinecourses.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Free Online Courses (Especially for ECE, CS and ME Students)" /><published>2019-04-10T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-10T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/10/best-onlinecourses</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/10/best-onlinecourses.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/best-courses/best-courses.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Best Courses&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know that courses we take in the college is not enough. It is always good to not limit yourself. You might want to go deeper in a subject that you are interested. It doesn’t matter whether it is directly related to your department or your academic interest. It is even better if you improve yourself with different concepts. This will help you to connect pieces together. Don’t forget that interdisciplinary work is the best!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I would like to share some &lt;strong&gt;free online courses&lt;/strong&gt; that could be useful. I took these courses in order to have necessary background for robotics. However, even if you aren’t interested in robotics, most of these courses would still be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;linear-algebra-by-prof-gilbert-strang&quot;&gt;Linear Algebra by Prof. Gilbert Strang&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without understanding linear algebra properly, it is impossible to understand the mathematical side of the concepts. I strongly recommend the course &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-06-linear-algebra-spring-2010/&quot;&gt;Linear Algebra by Prof. Gilbert Strang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mit---signals-and-systems-by-prof-alan-oppenheim&quot;&gt;MIT - Signals and Systems by Prof. Alan Oppenheim&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything in this life is either signal or system. Hence, either you study in simulation or real world, you will need to know &lt;strong&gt;Signals and Systems&lt;/strong&gt;. If you take any signal course during your undergraduate life, it is highly possible that you are biased to this course. Nonetheless, trust me, it is not that bad. Try to understand the concepts rather than memorizing Fourier formulas, laplace transforms etc. Remember that you are taking these courses to improve yourself, so just focus on learning! I believe &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/resources/res-6-007-signals-and-systems-spring-2011/&quot;&gt;MIT - Signals and Systems by Prof. Alan Oppenheim&lt;/a&gt; course is by far the best signal course ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mit---introduction-to-probability&quot;&gt;MIT - Introduction to Probability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are living in real world and nothing is deterministic. Every signal you measure is actually stochastic. Therefore, it is important to deal with uncertanity. After learning probability theory truly, you will see that life becomes much easy and you can understand the papers you read better. For this purpose, you can take &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/resources/res-6-012-introduction-to-probability-spring-2018/&quot;&gt;MIT - Introduction to Probability&lt;/a&gt; course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;embedded-systems---shape-the-world-microcontroller-inputoutput&quot;&gt;Embedded Systems - Shape The World: Microcontroller Input/Output&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we equipped ourselves with enough mathematical background. Now let’s 
try to implement some cool stuff. If you want to work on hardware &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/embedded-systems-shape-the-world-microcontroller-inputoutput&quot;&gt;Embedded Systems - Shape The World: Microcontroller Input/Output&lt;/a&gt; course will provide significant information for you. Thanks to this course, you can understand the limits of hardware. After getting this course, you will be able to write a program for an embedded platform and get to learn basic concepts such as clocks, interrupts, registers etc. If you want to be a hardware guy/girl, I suggest that you should first work on &lt;strong&gt;Arduino&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/strong&gt;. You can then take this course to learn further about embedded programming. Otherwise, the course would be a bit difficult to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;machine-learning-by-andrew-ng&quot;&gt;Machine Learning by Andrew Ng&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have heard something called &lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/strong&gt;, but you don’t know anything at all, then &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning&quot;&gt;Machine Learning by Andrew Ng&lt;/a&gt; course will be perfect starting point for you. Andrew Ng is one of the leading researchers in the machine learning field. He tries to teach both theoretical and practical side of the topic. The coding assignments of the course can be done in either &lt;strong&gt;MATLAB&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Octave&lt;/strong&gt;. I strongly suggest that take the assignments of this course seriously and spend enough effort on them. During the course, you can test your linear algebra knowledge as well since most of the theoretical part is composed of matrices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mit---deep-learning-for-self-driving-cars&quot;&gt;MIT - Deep Learning for Self Driving Cars&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you decide to go further in &lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/strong&gt; field, you can follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://selfdrivingcars.mit.edu/&quot;&gt;MIT - Deep Learning for Self Driving Cars&lt;/a&gt; course to learn &lt;strong&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a subfield of Machine learning. I always believe that learning something is much efficient if you are working on a project. This course provides exactly this. You learn Deep Learning better thanks to Self Driving Car aplications. It is also fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deep-reinforcement-learning-by-sergey-levine&quot;&gt;Deep Reinforcement Learning by Sergey Levine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reinforcement Learning (RL)&lt;/strong&gt; is also a subfield of machine learning and it is one of the recent hot research topics. One of the biggest advantage that RL provides is it doesn’t need a huge training dataset like &lt;strong&gt;Deep Learning Structures&lt;/strong&gt;. It can learn what to do by itself thanks to given rewards and punishments to the system. If you are interested in RL, you can take &lt;a href=&quot;http://rail.eecs.berkeley.edu/deeprlcourse/&quot;&gt;Deep Reinforcement Learning by Sergey Levine&lt;/a&gt; course. The lecturer Sergey Levine is a successful researcher in this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;upenn-robotics-micromaster&quot;&gt;Upenn Robotics MicroMaster&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in robotics and want to learn theoretical information specific to robotics, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/micromasters/pennx-robotics#courses&quot;&gt;Upenn Robotics MicroMaster&lt;/a&gt; will be perfect online course for you to follow. It offers various online courses such as  &lt;strong&gt;Robotics Kinematics&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Robotics Vision&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Robotics Dynamics and Control&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Robotics Locomotion&lt;/strong&gt; etc. I think it is also a perfect opportunity to test yourself and your interest in different subfields of robotics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all I want to say right now. If you also know other online courses that could be beneficial for other people, please use comment section and let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget that even if you are not at the department you like, you can still follow your passion. The only thing you need is a computer with an internet connection!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-procrastinating-and-do-something-to-reach-your-dreams&quot;&gt;STOP PROCRASTINATING AND DO SOMETHING TO REACH YOUR DREAMS!&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/best-courses/best-courses.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Apply a Graduate Program?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/03/graduate-application.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Apply a Graduate Program?" /><published>2019-04-03T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-03T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/03/graduate-application</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/03/graduate-application.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/grad-school.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Graduate Application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have some dream colleges in your mind, and you want to apply a graduate program in these colleges. However, you don’t know where to start and which documents you need. Don’t worry! In this post, I will try to explain graduate programme application procedure by providing an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you need to decide is which department you want to apply. Sometimes, there are more than one department related to your research interest. If this is the case, you can check your professor of interest’s department and courses given by the departments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at an example application. Suppose that you are interested in robotics and you want to consider University of Washington’s graduate programme. There are several departments related to robotics like Electrical and Computer Engineering, Computer Science Department or Mechanical Engineering. Some universities even has special Robotics Ph.D. programme like Carnegie Mellon University (CMU).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, search &lt;strong&gt;University of Washington Robotics&lt;/strong&gt; in Google and visit the corresponding website.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have learned that &lt;strong&gt;Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering Department&lt;/strong&gt; seems to have has various labs related to robotics. Let’s proceed further to find out specific graduate program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Research &amp;amp; Innovation&lt;/strong&gt; button at the top.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the new Research &amp;amp; Innovation Tab, click &lt;strong&gt;graduate program&lt;/strong&gt; link.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can see general information such as how many students are admitted to this program, application deadline etc.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we haven’t seen required documents and minimum requirements for this graduate program yet. Click &lt;strong&gt;Admissions&lt;/strong&gt; Tab at the top.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/6.png&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/7.png&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yey! This is the place that we are looking for. As you can see there is a link &lt;strong&gt;APPLY NOW&lt;/strong&gt; at the end of &lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt; section. You will be applying using this link, but before we need to learn minimum requirements to apply this program. For this purpose, click &lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/strong&gt; tab.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/8.png&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in this page the requirements are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The completion of a bachelor’s degree and a 3.0 GPA in the latest two years&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The average GRE scores of recent applicants were: Verbal 83% (including international applicants), Quantitative 93%, and Analytical 61%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some courses you should took during your undergraduate time like data structures, discrete math, automata theory etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For international students: The minimum TOEFL-iBT score is 80, including at least 26 on the Speaking section of the test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/9.png&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s check &lt;strong&gt;Required Materials&lt;/strong&gt; section.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/10.png&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can clearly see all the required materials in this webpage with all necessary information. Generally required documents for a graduate program is typical. For this case they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statement of Purpose (SOP)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Curriculum Vitae (CV)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three Letters of Recommendation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List of Faculty Interest (Professors of Interest)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GRE Score&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TOEFL Score&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unofficial Transcript&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application Fee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Unfortunately you need to pay an application fee for almost all the graduate applications to colleges in USA :(. You will pay this fee at the end of your application (after submitting everything).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions in your mind, don’t forget to check Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ) section. You are going to realize that almost all the questions in your mind are answered here.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/11.png&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you know all the necessary documents and conditions to apply. Go &lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt; part and click &lt;strong&gt;Apply Now&lt;/strong&gt; button.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/12.png&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each university has different websites for application, but everything is almost same. You are going to create a profile in the university’s application portal. In this portal, you are going to choose the exact program you want to apply, and you need to fill many information about yourself and your education. This portal also provides you to upload necessary documents.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/13.png&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Please be aware of the fact that even filling forms in the application websites for the universities takes a lot of time. For example, if you are going to apply for a graduate school directly after undergraduate, you will need to do this applications in your last year as an undergraduate student. Therefore, don’t fill forms late since you don’t want to spend significant time for this in your exam week. My biggest advice for you guys is that you should fill the forms for the universities that you are planning to apply for a graduate program whenever you have time. Even if you haven’t taken the TOEFL or the GRE it doesn’t matter. You can still fill the forms. Moreover, you can also fill the forms for the schools that you might apply, but you are not sure. If you don’t submit the application then it will not be processed. All of this will save lots of time. Trust me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on the applied university and program, the process and documents may vary, but more or the less it is the same. Regarding the applications you can see my other posts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://samialperen.github.io/2019/03/26/gre-preparation.html&quot;&gt;How to Study for the GRE?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://samialperen.github.io/2019/03/08/toefl-preparation.html&quot;&gt;How to study for the TOEFL? Where to Start?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for this post. If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to use comment section. I wish you will be accepted to your dream school!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/graduate-application/grad-school.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Study for the GRE?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/26/gre-preparation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Study for the GRE?" /><published>2019-03-26T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-03-26T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/26/gre-preparation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/26/gre-preparation.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/gre/gre-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;GRE&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to apply for a graduate school, you will probably need to take the GRE test. Generally, most of the colleges in USA requires GRE while some colleges in Canada or Europe also requires GRE score for application. You should check each school of your interest to see whether they need a GRE score or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say (unluckily) you need a GRE score to apply your dream school. You started to search for online to learn what the GRE is and how to study. However, you found a lot of information, and you got lost. You can be relaxed now because this post is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-gre&quot;&gt;What is GRE?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRE is composed of three different parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analytical Writing: 2 Questions per Section – 1 Section Total&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Verbal Reasoning (Verbal): 20 Questions per Section – 2 Section Total&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quantitative Reasoning (Quant): 20 Questions per Section –2 Section Total&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, you will have an experimental unscored section which will be either Verbal or Quant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Score ranges of these three different parts are (Minimum to Maximum):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analytical Writing: 0-6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Verbal: 130-170&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quant: 130-170&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GRE scores are a bit strange especially for Verbal or Quant parts. If you did not give a correct answer to any questions in these parts, you will 
get 130 score, and if you answered all questions correctly, you will get 170 max score in that part. You might think that in this case each question has 1 point since Verbal and Quant sections has 40 questions total. However, this is the confusing part. GRE scores are not linear. If you had only one wrong answers, this does not mean that you will get 169 score. I know this is confusing, but unfortunately this is the situation. Don’t mind about scores, just try to get maximum score possible. In any case, if you are curious about GRE scores, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ets.org/gre/revised_general/scores/how/&quot;&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt;. You can also follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaptest.com/gre/what-is-the-gre&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about GRE sections individually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-study&quot;&gt;How to Study?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After registering for the GRE using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ets.org/gre&quot;&gt;ETS Website&lt;/a&gt;, it will give you two different example question sets to study for the GRE. I recommend you to solve these tests at the last stage like one day before the real exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, check minimum requirements of each school that you are applying and specify your target score for each part of the GRE. For example, if you are an engineering student, most probably you need to score perfect in Quant section, moderate in Analytical Writing section and relatively poor in Verbal part. Of course, scoring perfect in all sections is the best, but not achievable in short term. Furthermore, I am not sure that you even need to score perfect in Verbal for engineering applications since it is quite difficult and even natives have hard times during the test. As I mentioned before, checking minimum requirements of applied schools could be nice guideline for you to determine target score for each part of the GRE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After determining your target score, you should start to learn about question types in each part of the exam. Like the TOEFL, understanding question types and specific answers for them is essential to succeed. For this purpose, I would recommend you to use &lt;strong&gt;The Princeton Review: Cracking the GRE PREMIUM&lt;/strong&gt; book. It is published each year, so please try to use the newest one. This book will introduce you all question types in different sections and give tips how to approach them. You can either follow all the sections or just the ones that you feel week. Personally, I believe if you are an engineering student, you won’t even need to look for Quant section because it is super easy for a person who has enough engineering background in math.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After studying all the question types and specific answer to them in different sections, now you are actually ready to practice. For practice, I can recommend you to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://gre.kmf.com/&quot;&gt;GRE kmf website&lt;/a&gt;. This website perfectly mimics the original GRE system and all the exams in &lt;strong&gt;Model Test&lt;/strong&gt; section are real exams which are used in the past. In my opinion, the difficulty of the original exam is almost same with the exams in &lt;strong&gt;kmf&lt;/strong&gt;. However, you may need a &lt;strong&gt;chinise VPN&lt;/strong&gt; to reach the website. To learn how to achieve this, please visit my &lt;a href=&quot;https://samialperen.github.io/2019/03/08/toefl-preparation.html&quot;&gt;TOEFL preperation post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I can recommend some apps to install on your mobile phone for GRE preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Magoosh GRE Flashcards: This app is perfect for vocabulary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Galvanize GRE Test Prep Math &amp;amp; Verbal: This application provides example questions for GRE. You can use this app to be familiar with all kinds of questions. It is especially very useful to use while you commute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are good at math, you can prepare for GRE within one or two week easily. If your math is not very good (which is totally fine), it may take up to 2-3 months to fully prepare for the exam depending on your level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish this post will be useful, and you will be able to reach your target score!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/gre/gre-logo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Sources to Follow Robotics Research and Stay Tuned</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/19/robotics-resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Sources to Follow Robotics Research and Stay Tuned" /><published>2019-03-19T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-03-19T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/19/robotics-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/19/robotics-resources.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/robotics-sources/Robotics2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Robotics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in robotics and want to learn recent research done in the field, I have some suggestions for you to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;robohub&quot;&gt;Robohub&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robohub is an amazing website to follow robotics research. It provides daily news about robotics, but the best thing I like about Robohub is &lt;strong&gt;Robohub Podcasts&lt;/strong&gt;. While you are commuting to college/work, listening these podcasts informs you about recent work of professors, graduate students and companies in Robotics. You can visit Robohub website using &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;. Robohub podcasts can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/podcast/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or you can follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/robohubpodcast&quot;&gt;Robohub Channel&lt;/a&gt; on Soundcloud. In this way, you also have a chance to listen these amazing podcasts on your mobile phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cmu-ri-seminars&quot;&gt;CMU RI Seminars&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carnegie Mellon University Robotics Institute (CMU-RI) holds excellent seminars regarding all subfields of Robotics. In these seminars, very successfull researchers introduces their recent research in robotics to CMU students. Fortunately, CMU records these seminars and publishes them on their Youtube channel. Please don’t forget to visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/cmurobotics&quot;&gt;CMU RI Youtube Channel&lt;/a&gt;. It would be wisely to watch these videos instead of killing time in computer game videos :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ieee-spectrum---robotics&quot;&gt;IEEE Spectrum - Robotics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is impossible to not mentioning about IEEE Spectrum when the subject is related to engineering. &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/robotics&quot;&gt;IEEE Spectrum - Robotics&lt;/a&gt; provides the newest information about robotics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;singularity-hub---robotics&quot;&gt;Singularity Hub - Robotics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it is not updated as frequently as IEEE Spectrum, &lt;a href=&quot;https://singularityhub.com/tag/robotics&quot;&gt;Singularity Hub - Robotics&lt;/a&gt; section can be a good source to discover fascinating work in robotics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many other sources to follow. You can check them via &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.feedspot.com/robot_blogs/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;. I just tried to give my favourite ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conferences--journals&quot;&gt;Conferences &amp;amp; Journals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want to mention about some well-known robotic conferences &amp;amp; journals. Attending one of the conferences would be fantastic, but generally not quite possible. However, even if you don’t attend, you should check later for published papers. They generally don’t make published papers directly available to public in a short time, i.e. it takes some time to reach these papers online. However, you can use previously mentioned sources to follow conferences. These sources usually creates some special edition posts for conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn dates of all IEEE Conferences via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ieee.org/conferences&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; at “Upcoming Conferences” section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the best Robotics Conferences &amp;amp; Journals that I follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conferences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ieee-ras.org/conferences-workshops/fully-sponsored/icra&quot;&gt;IEEE International Conference on Robotics And Automation (ICRA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ieee-ras.org/conferences-workshops/financially-co-sponsored/iros&quot;&gt;International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.roboticsconference.org/&quot;&gt;Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ijrr.org/&quot;&gt;The International Journal of Robotics Research (IJRR)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/servlet/opac?punumber=8860&quot;&gt;IEEE Transactions on Robotics (T-RO)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I would like to talk about &lt;strong&gt;ResearchGate&lt;/strong&gt; website. I can simply say that it is Facebook of scientists and engineers. My favorite thing about this website is when you add your research of interest to your profile, &lt;strong&gt;ResearchGate&lt;/strong&gt; suggests you possible papers regarding your research interest. You can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to visit the website. For this purpose, you can use &lt;strong&gt;Mendeley&lt;/strong&gt; as well. Please visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mendeley.com/&quot;&gt;Mendeley Website&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for this post. I hope you like it. If you know other sources, feel free to use comment section.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/robotics-sources/Robotics2.jpg" /></entry></feed>