<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-22T19:28:03+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Personal Blog of Sami Alperen Akgün</title><subtitle>Welcome to my personal blog! In this blog, I will try to share my experience and thoughts about academic life, travel, literature technology, music, movies and TV-series. You can use/share any information in here as long as you provide reference. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">How to Apply a Graduate Program?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/03/graduate-application.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Apply a Graduate Program?" /><published>2019-04-03T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-03T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/03/graduate-application</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/03/graduate-application.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/grad-school.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Graduate Application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have some dream colleges in your mind, and you want to apply a graduate program in these colleges. However, you don’t know where to start and which documents you need. Don’t worry! In this post, I will try to explain graduate programme application procedure by providing an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you need to decide is which department you want to apply. Sometimes, there are more than one department related to your research interest. If this is the case, you can check your professor of interest’s department and courses given by the departments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at an example application. Suppose that you are interested in robotics and you want to consider University of Washington’s graduate programme. There are several departments related to robotics like Electrical and Computer Engineering, Computer Science Department or Mechanical Engineering. Some universities even has special Robotics Ph.D. programme like Carnegie Mellon University (CMU).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, search &lt;strong&gt;University of Washington Robotics&lt;/strong&gt; in Google and visit the corresponding website.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have learned that &lt;strong&gt;Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering Department&lt;/strong&gt; seems to have has various labs related to robotics. Let’s proceed further to find out specific graduate program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Research &amp;amp; Innovation&lt;/strong&gt; button at the top.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the new Research &amp;amp; Innovation Tab, click &lt;strong&gt;graduate program&lt;/strong&gt; link.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can see general information such as how many students are admitted to this program, application deadline etc.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we haven’t seen required documents and minimum requirements for this graduate program yet. Click &lt;strong&gt;Admissions&lt;/strong&gt; Tab at the top.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/6.png&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/7.png&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yey! This is the place that we are looking for. As you can see there is a link &lt;strong&gt;APPLY NOW&lt;/strong&gt; at the end of &lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt; section. You will be applying using this link, but before we need to learn minimum requirements to apply this program. For this purpose, click &lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/strong&gt; tab.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/8.png&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in this page the requirements are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The completion of a bachelor’s degree and a 3.0 GPA in the latest two years&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The average GRE scores of recent applicants were: Verbal 83% (including international applicants), Quantitative 93%, and Analytical 61%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some courses you should took during your undergraduate time like data structures, discrete math, automata theory etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For international students: The minimum TOEFL-iBT score is 80, including at least 26 on the Speaking section of the test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/9.png&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s check &lt;strong&gt;Required Materials&lt;/strong&gt; section.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/10.png&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can clearly see all the required materials in this webpage with all necessary information. Generally required documents for a graduate program is typical. For this case they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statement of Purpose (SOP)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Curriculum Vitae (CV)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three Letters of Recommendation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List of Faculty Interest (Professors of Interest)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GRE Score&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TOEFL Score&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unofficial Transcript&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application Fee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Unfortunately you need to pay an application fee for almost all the graduate applications to colleges in USA :(. You will pay this fee at the end of your application (after submitting everything).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions in your mind, don’t forget to check Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ) section. You are going to realize that almost all the questions in your mind are answered here.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/11.png&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you know all the necessary documents and conditions to apply. Go &lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt; part and click &lt;strong&gt;Apply Now&lt;/strong&gt; button.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/12.png&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each university has different websites for application, but everything is almost same. You are going to create a profile in the university’s application portal. In this portal, you are going to choose the exact program you want to apply, and you need to fill many information about yourself and your education. This portal also provides you to upload necessary documents.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/graduate-application/13.png&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Please be aware of the fact that even filling forms in the application websites for the universities takes a lot of time. For example, if you are going to apply for a graduate school directly after undergraduate, you will need to do this applications in your last year as an undergraduate student. Therefore, don’t fill forms late since you don’t want to spend significant time for this in your exam week. My biggest advice for you guys is that you should fill the forms for the universities that you are planning to apply for a graduate program whenever you have time. Even if you haven’t taken the TOEFL or the GRE it doesn’t matter. You can still fill the forms. Moreover, you can also fill the forms for the schools that you might apply, but you are not sure. If you don’t submit the application then it will not be processed. All of this will save lots of time. Trust me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on the applied university and program, the process and documents may vary, but more or the less it is the same. Regarding the applications you can see my other posts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://samialperen.github.io/2019/03/26/gre-preparation.html&quot;&gt;How to Study for the GRE?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://samialperen.github.io/2019/03/08/toefl-preparation.html&quot;&gt;How to study for the TOEFL? Where to Start?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for this post. If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to use comment section. I wish you will be accepted to your dream school!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/graduate-application/grad-school.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Study for the GRE?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/26/gre-preparation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Study for the GRE?" /><published>2019-03-26T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-03-26T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/26/gre-preparation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/26/gre-preparation.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/gre/gre-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;GRE&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to apply for a graduate school, you will probably need to take the GRE test. Generally, most of the colleges in USA requires GRE while some colleges in Canada or Europe also requires GRE score for application. You should check each school of your interest to see whether they need a GRE score or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say (unluckily) you need a GRE score to apply your dream school. You started to search for online to learn what the GRE is and how to study. However, you found a lot of information, and you got lost. You can be relaxed now because this post is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-gre&quot;&gt;What is GRE?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRE is composed of three different parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analytical Writing: 2 Questions per Section – 1 Section Total&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Verbal Reasoning (Verbal): 20 Questions per Section – 2 Section Total&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quantitative Reasoning (Quant): 20 Questions per Section –2 Section Total&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, you will have an experimental unscored section which will be either Verbal or Quant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Score ranges of these three different parts are (Minimum to Maximum):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analytical Writing: 0-6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Verbal: 130-170&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quant: 130-170&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GRE scores are a bit strange especially for Verbal or Quant parts. If you did not give a correct answer to any questions in these parts, you will 
get 130 score, and if you answered all questions correctly, you will get 170 max score in that part. You might think that in this case each question has 1 point since Verbal and Quant sections has 40 questions total. However, this is the confusing part. GRE scores are not linear. If you had only one wrong answers, this does not mean that you will get 169 score. I know this is confusing, but unfortunately this is the situation. Don’t mind about scores, just try to get maximum score possible. In any case, if you are curious about GRE scores, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ets.org/gre/revised_general/scores/how/&quot;&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt;. You can also follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaptest.com/gre/what-is-the-gre&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about GRE sections individually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-study&quot;&gt;How to Study?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After registering for the GRE using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ets.org/gre&quot;&gt;ETS Website&lt;/a&gt;, it will give you two different example question sets to study for the GRE. I recommend you to solve these tests at the last stage like one day before the real exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, check minimum requirements of each school that you are applying and specify your target score for each part of the GRE. For example, if you are an engineering student, most probably you need to score perfect in Quant section, moderate in Analytical Writing section and relatively poor in Verbal part. Of course, scoring perfect in all sections is the best, but not achievable in short term. Furthermore, I am not sure that you even need to score perfect in Verbal for engineering applications since it is quite difficult and even natives have hard times during the test. As I mentioned before, checking minimum requirements of applied schools could be nice guideline for you to determine target score for each part of the GRE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After determining your target score, you should start to learn about question types in each part of the exam. Like the TOEFL, understanding question types and specific answers for them is essential to succeed. For this purpose, I would recommend you to use &lt;strong&gt;The Princeton Review: Cracking the GRE PREMIUM&lt;/strong&gt; book. It is published each year, so please try to use the newest one. This book will introduce you all question types in different sections and give tips how to approach them. You can either follow all the sections or just the ones that you feel week. Personally, I believe if you are an engineering student, you won’t even need to look for Quant section because it is super easy for a person who has enough engineering background in math.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After studying all the question types and specific answer to them in different sections, now you are actually ready to practice. For practice, I can recommend you to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://gre.kmf.com/&quot;&gt;GRE kmf website&lt;/a&gt;. This website perfectly mimics the original GRE system and all the exams in &lt;strong&gt;Model Test&lt;/strong&gt; section are real exams which are used in the past. In my opinion, the difficulty of the original exam is almost same with the exams in &lt;strong&gt;kmf&lt;/strong&gt;. However, you may need a &lt;strong&gt;chinise VPN&lt;/strong&gt; to reach the website. To learn how to achieve this, please visit my &lt;a href=&quot;https://samialperen.github.io/2019/03/08/toefl-preparation.html&quot;&gt;TOEFL preperation post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I can recommend some apps to install on your mobile phone for GRE preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Magoosh GRE Flashcards: This app is perfect for vocabulary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Galvanize GRE Test Prep Math &amp;amp; Verbal: This application provides example questions for GRE. You can use this app to be familiar with all kinds of questions. It is especially very useful to use while you commute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are good at math, you can prepare for GRE within one or two week easily. If your math is not very good (which is totally fine), it may take up to 2-3 months to fully prepare for the exam depending on your level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish this post will be useful, and you will be able to reach your target score!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/gre/gre-logo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Sources to Follow Robotics Research and Stay Tuned</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/19/robotics-resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Sources to Follow Robotics Research and Stay Tuned" /><published>2019-03-19T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-03-19T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/19/robotics-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/19/robotics-resources.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/robotics-sources/Robotics2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Robotics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in robotics and want to learn recent research done in the field, I have some suggestions for you to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;robohub&quot;&gt;Robohub&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robohub is an amazing website to follow robotics research. It provides daily news about robotics, but the best thing I like about Robohub is &lt;strong&gt;Robohub Podcasts&lt;/strong&gt;. While you are commuting to college/work, listening these podcasts informs you about recent work of professors, graduate students and companies in Robotics. You can visit Robohub website using &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;. Robohub podcasts can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://robohub.org/podcast/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or you can follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/robohubpodcast&quot;&gt;Robohub Channel&lt;/a&gt; on Soundcloud. In this way, you also have a chance to listen these amazing podcasts on your mobile phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cmu-ri-seminars&quot;&gt;CMU RI Seminars&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carnegie Mellon University Robotics Institute (CMU-RI) holds excellent seminars regarding all subfields of Robotics. In these seminars, very successfull researchers introduces their recent research in robotics to CMU students. Fortunately, CMU records these seminars and publishes them on their Youtube channel. Please don’t forget to visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/cmurobotics&quot;&gt;CMU RI Youtube Channel&lt;/a&gt;. It would be wisely to watch these videos instead of killing time in computer game videos :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ieee-spectrum---robotics&quot;&gt;IEEE Spectrum - Robotics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is impossible to not mentioning about IEEE Spectrum when the subject is related to engineering. &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/robotics&quot;&gt;IEEE Spectrum - Robotics&lt;/a&gt; provides the newest information about robotics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;singularity-hub---robotics&quot;&gt;Singularity Hub - Robotics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it is not updated as frequently as IEEE Spectrum, &lt;a href=&quot;https://singularityhub.com/tag/robotics&quot;&gt;Singularity Hub - Robotics&lt;/a&gt; section can be a good source to discover fascinating work in robotics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many other sources to follow. You can check them via &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.feedspot.com/robot_blogs/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;. I just tried to give my favourite ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conferences--journals&quot;&gt;Conferences &amp;amp; Journals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want to mention about some well-known robotic conferences &amp;amp; journals. Attending one of the conferences would be fantastic, but generally not quite possible. However, even if you don’t attend, you should check later for published papers. They generally don’t make published papers directly available to public in a short time, i.e. it takes some time to reach these papers online. However, you can use previously mentioned sources to follow conferences. These sources usually creates some special edition posts for conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn dates of all IEEE Conferences via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ieee.org/conferences&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; at “Upcoming Conferences” section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the best Robotics Conferences &amp;amp; Journals that I follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conferences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ieee-ras.org/conferences-workshops/fully-sponsored/icra&quot;&gt;IEEE International Conference on Robotics And Automation (ICRA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ieee-ras.org/conferences-workshops/financially-co-sponsored/iros&quot;&gt;International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.roboticsconference.org/&quot;&gt;Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ijrr.org/&quot;&gt;The International Journal of Robotics Research (IJRR)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/servlet/opac?punumber=8860&quot;&gt;IEEE Transactions on Robotics (T-RO)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I would like to talk about &lt;strong&gt;ResearchGate&lt;/strong&gt; website. I can simply say that it is Facebook of scientists and engineers. My favorite thing about this website is when you add your research of interest to your profile, &lt;strong&gt;ResearchGate&lt;/strong&gt; suggests you possible papers regarding your research interest. You can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to visit the website. For this purpose, you can use &lt;strong&gt;Mendeley&lt;/strong&gt; as well. Please visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mendeley.com/&quot;&gt;Mendeley Website&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for this post. I hope you like it. If you know other sources, feel free to use comment section.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/robotics-sources/Robotics2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to study for the TOEFL? Where to Start?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/08/toefl-preparation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to study for the TOEFL? Where to Start?" /><published>2019-03-08T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-03-08T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/08/toefl-preparation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/08/toefl-preparation.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/toefl/toefl.png&quot; alt=&quot;TOEFL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to take the TOEFL, and you have limited time to study. You start to search online for study tips and materials and &lt;strong&gt;WOW!&lt;/strong&gt;. There are too much information and you do not know where to start. Do not worry, I had the same situation, but I managed to solve it. In this post, I will try to explain my own strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, you need to become familiar with the TOEFL and its sections. For this purpose, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notefull.com/&quot;&gt;Notefull&lt;/a&gt;. In this website, click &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notefull.com/content.php?pgID=575&quot;&gt;TOEFL Help - Free Trial&lt;/a&gt; and read/watch all materials respectively. &lt;strong&gt;Notefull&lt;/strong&gt; will provide you the background information about the exam and all question types in a detailed manner with specific tricks for each section. Take some notes during Notefull videos and create some templates to use later during practice (especially for speaking).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting all the necessary information and tricks, you are now ready to make practice. Please do not forget that, it is only matter of practice for you to get your dream score of TOEFL. Therefore, keep up hardwork and practice as much as possible. Start practising with original &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ets.org/toefl/ibt/prepare/toefl_interactive_sampler&quot;&gt;TOEFL iBT Interactive Sampler&lt;/a&gt;. Then, you can visit great chinese website &lt;a href=&quot;https://toefl.kmf.com/&quot;&gt;toefl kmf&lt;/a&gt;
to make more practice. Convert the language of website to English and go for &lt;strong&gt;Model Test&lt;/strong&gt; tab at the top of the website. This website perfectly mimics the original TOEFL system and all the exams in &lt;strong&gt;Model Test&lt;/strong&gt; section are real exams which are used in the past. I personally could say that the difficulty of the original exam is almost same with the exams in &lt;strong&gt;kmf&lt;/strong&gt;. Normally, the website is closed for users outside of China, but you can access it with a VPN. For this purpose, I recommend to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/search/hola&quot;&gt;Hola VPN&lt;/a&gt;. Do not forget to select VPN location to &lt;strong&gt;China!&lt;/strong&gt; I also recommend to use Google Chrome as a web-browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see your improvement in &lt;strong&gt;Reading&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Listening&lt;/strong&gt; sections as you practice. Nonetheless, knowing where you are and what is your score in &lt;strong&gt;Speaking&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Writing&lt;/strong&gt; sections are not possible. Therefore, I strongly recommend to take a feedback in these sections from someone who is familiar with the TOEFL. Otherwise, you might have an illusion that you are good at &lt;strong&gt;Speaking&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Writing&lt;/strong&gt; section while in the reality this is quite far away from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time, try to make practice tests in an environment where you are not comfortable and some noise exists in order to simulate real TOEFL conditions. Aside from making practice, you also need to learn to focus even if there exists distraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can not get your target score, do not be sad. Remember that TOEFL does not measure your proficieny in English. It measures how much you know the exam format. This is sad, but unfortunately true! Therefore, do not lose your hope. Analyze your mistakes and start to practice from the section which you did not perform well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you will be succesfull!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/toefl/toefl.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Find a Flat in Europe (Specifically in Berlin)?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/02/accommodation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Find a Flat in Europe (Specifically in Berlin)?" /><published>2019-03-02T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-03-02T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/02/accommodation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/02/accommodation.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/accommodation_berlin/berlinfromreichstag.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Berlin Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt; Picture 1: View from the top of Reichstag Building &lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I am going to share my knowledge about how to find a flat in Europe. I will explain everything using Berlin example because I had quite difficult times to find an accommodation for short (3 month duration) stay in Berlin. However, you can use same tricks and methods to find an accommodation in any place. Only websites and names will be changed. In here, I will try to give a general guideline to start. Of course, everything will be depended on your effort and luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be wondering why finding a place to rent could be a problem if you are not used to it. If this is the case, you will be surprised. The main reason behind this is that more and more people moves to favorite cities in Europe, but available property number stays constant. For example, Berlin is one of the problematic cities regarding this issue because although it is a capital of Germany, it is still way cheaper than capitals of other European countries. &lt;strong&gt;Berliners&lt;/strong&gt; (people who live in Berlin) search a place for rent even if they do not need to. This becomes a habit for Berliners. You should be the same! This is the first rule.  :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess you understand importance of the problem, but how to solve it? My first suggestion is that you should start to look for a place as soon as possible. Please don’t wait until the last minute! The best option is arranging a place before arrival. Otherwise, it is highly possible that you will find a place either too far away from the center or too expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some alternatives to rent a flat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1-)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/&quot;&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2-)&lt;/strong&gt; Totally Empty House&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3-)&lt;/strong&gt; Shared Room (Wohngemeinschaft (WG) in German)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4-)&lt;/strong&gt; Furnished Apartments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; generally costs too much for duration of stays longer than 30 day, so it is not suggested. However, in the worst case you can stay in Airbnb in your first weeks to find a place. Keep this in mind!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not know too much about Number &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;, but you can try to visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.immobilienscout24.de/wohnen/mietwohnungen.html&quot;&gt;Immobilienscout24&lt;/a&gt;. Nonetheless, it is obvious that renting a totally empty house is not suggested since it is too tiring for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; is too common in Berlin. In shared rooms you have a personal room in a normal house, but other parts of the house is common like kitchen and bathroom. Different people are looking for different tenants and housemates. Hence, please be honest and say your expectations from the flat. For instance, if you want to stay in a calm and silent place, you should not stay with housemates who makes home parties. I think WGs are the best option for students and newcomers to city. It is cheap and you will have a chance to meet and live with different people and get to know the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to find a WG, you can either use well-known and widely used websites or facebook groups. However, please be careful since there are a lot of &lt;strong&gt;scam&lt;/strong&gt; posts and &lt;strong&gt;cheaters&lt;/strong&gt; to foul people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common websites to find a WG:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wg-gesucht.de/&quot;&gt;wg-gesucht&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.studenten-wg.de&quot;&gt;studenten-wg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wg-suche.de/&quot;&gt;wg-suche&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wgfinden.de&quot;&gt;wg-finden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to find facebook groups search for “WG in Berlin”, “Shared Room in Berlin”, “Erasmus Berlin 2019” etc. keywords in Facebook. In these groups, you can check available rooms. You can also create a post to state your need of WG, but again be careful about &lt;strong&gt;scam&lt;/strong&gt;! Here are some facebook groups that I know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/79516702871/?fref=ts&quot;&gt;Nett-Werk Berlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/WG.Zimmer.frei.in.Berlin?fref=ts&quot;&gt;Shared Rooms in Berlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/wg.wohnung.berlin/&quot;&gt;WG-Zimmer &amp;amp; Wohnungen Berlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/wg.zimmer.wohnung.berlin.room.flat.apartment/?ref=br_rs&quot;&gt;WG Zimmer Wohnung&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also join the facebook group &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/1744464679140962/?ref=br_rs&quot;&gt;New Wave in Berlin&lt;/a&gt;. This group was founded by young Turkish people to create a platform for solidarity. Even if you are not Turkish, feel free to send a request to join. You can ask any question in this group regarding Berlin or Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; is preferred mostly by people who either do not want to live with other people or have a family. Most of the furnished apartments are studio or 1+1. If you are looking for an house with 2 bedrooms, then you will need to spend more time. As far as I know, landlords may be too meticulous about their tenant selection, so try to be specific and explain every criterion of yourself and do not get offended by rejections. Here are some websites that I have heard to find furnished apartments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wunderflats.com/&quot;&gt;wunderflats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.coming-home.org/suche_2.php?Ort=Berlin&quot;&gt;coming-home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spotahome.com/berlin&quot;&gt;spotahome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.white-apartments.com/&quot;&gt;white-apartments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The procedure will be more or less same with other cities. I personally applied same procedure to find an accommodation in London and it works! Of course you need to find corresponding websites or groups. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish good luck for your seeking. You can see pictures of Bulowstrasse and Dennewitzplatz, where my shared room was located. I found this place two weeks before of my arrival to Berlin, so whatever happens, do not give up hope!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/accommodation_berlin/bulowstrasse.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bulowstrasse&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt; Picture 2: Bulowstrasse - Schoneberg &lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/accommodation_berlin/dennewitzplatz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dennewitzplatz&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt; Picture 3: Dennewitzplatz and American Church &lt;/center&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Picture 1: View from the top of Reichstag Building</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/accommodation_berlin/berlinfromreichstag.JPG" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Convert .py to .exe without Requiring a Python Installation to Windows</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/18/py2exe.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Convert .py to .exe without Requiring a Python Installation to Windows" /><published>2019-02-18T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-02-18T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/18/py2exe</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/18/py2exe.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/py2exe/py2exe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Py2Exe Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT:&lt;/strong&gt; If you are using different libraries, installing Python directly to Windows could be cumbersome. Configuring py2exe’s “setup.py” may also require extra effort. I offer another alternative for this case. Please see at the end of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you may need to convert your .py scripts into Windows executables. All we want is actually very clear. We want to create self compatible Windows executable files from .py scripts so that they can run in Windows machines without requiring any further installation to Windows machine. Thankfully, there is a nice and easy way to do this, which is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.py2exe.org/&quot;&gt;py2exe&lt;/a&gt;. According to the original source of py2exe, py2exe is a &lt;strong&gt;Python Distutils&lt;/strong&gt; extension which converts Python scripts into executable Windows programs, able to run without requiring a Python installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; You will need to install proper Python version to your Windows machine to make this conversion using py2exe. In this case, you can say “But you said without requiring a Python Installation!”. Well, what we mean by this phrase is that once you made this conversion, you can run converted .exe files in any Windows machine and you do not need to install anything to that machines. However, you need to install required programs to make this conversion. Now, I guess it is more clear, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s learn how to install Python and py2exe and lastly an example conversion from .py into .exe using py2exe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING!:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;You need to do these operations in Windows.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1-python-installation&quot;&gt;Step 1: Python Installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download python from official website. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/downloads/release/python-343/&quot;&gt;python 3.4.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING!:&lt;/strong&gt; py2exe has some compatibility problems with higher versions of Python. Therefore, if it is not required, do not use python version 3.5. or more. If it is a must for you then, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/41570359/how-can-i-convert-a-py-to-exe-for-python&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; stackoverflow discussion might help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download Windows x86 MSI Installer if you are using 64 bit machine. Install python using the installer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;C:\Python34&lt;/code&gt; (default location for installation)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In customize python screen click down arrow button and choose Entire feature will be installed on local drive as you can see below.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/py2exe/customize_python_screen.png&quot; alt=&quot;Customize python screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next and next and wait for installation to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Python 3.4.3 installer automatically adjust environmental variable paths, so hopefully you will not have any problem.
However, if you have any problem, follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://simpletutorials.com/c/1613/How+to+Add+Python+3+directories+to+your+PATH+in+Windows+7&quot;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of difficulty, &lt;a href=&quot;https://simpletutorials.com/c/1522/Installing+Python+3+%2832+bit%29+on+Windows&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is an another tutorial to install python into Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-py2exe-installation&quot;&gt;Step 2: py2exe Installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open windows commandline (cmd) and go to the directory which contain installed python scripts. If you chose default directory to install python
then it will be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd C:\Python34\Scripts
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install py2exe using pip&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ pip install py2exe
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3-convert-your-py-script-to-exe&quot;&gt;Step 3: Convert your .py Script to .exe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First you need to create a &lt;strong&gt;setup.py&lt;/strong&gt; script which calls py2exe and your script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose you have a python script named hello.py and you want to convert it to .exe. In this case an example setup.py will be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;from distutils.core import setup
import py2exe

setup(console=['hello.py'])
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; It is important that both setup.py and hello.py should be in same directory. Otherwise you need to edit setup.py to show absolute path directory of your script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you put your setup.py and hello.py in a directory named Tutorial whose location is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;C:\Tutorial&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From windows cmd go to that directory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd C:\Tutorial
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And run setup.py&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ python setup.py py2exe
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everything goes fine, you will be able to see hello.exe in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;C:\Tutorial\Dist&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;edit-for-python-scripts-with-lots-of-library-imports&quot;&gt;EDIT: For Python Scripts with Lots of Library Imports&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, if you are using different libraries, installing Python directly to Windows could be cumbersome. Configuring py2exe’s “setup.py” may also require extra effort. For this case, I will recommend you to use either &lt;strong&gt;Anaconda&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Miniconda&lt;/strong&gt; to install Python to Windows and use &lt;strong&gt;pyinstaller&lt;/strong&gt; instead of &lt;strong&gt;py2exe&lt;/strong&gt; to convert .py scripts to .exe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I generally use Python &lt;strong&gt;Pandas&lt;/strong&gt; library a lot and it is generally difficult to install it to Windows. I used Pyinstaller with Miniconda to convert my python script with Pandas library to windows executable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First, follow &lt;a href=&quot;http://pandas.pydata.org/pandas-docs/version/0.19/install.html&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to install Python to Windows using Anaconda/Miniconda.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Install the libraries you used in python script. (Using pip will be advantageous)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go to your .py script directory and run Pyinstaller.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ pyinstaller your_script.py
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it! I hope this will be useful for you. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/py2exe/py2exe.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">İngiltere Erasmus Stajı Vizesi Nasıl Alınır? (Tier 5 Vize Başvurusu)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/17/ingiltere-vizesi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="İngiltere Erasmus Stajı Vizesi Nasıl Alınır? (Tier 5 Vize Başvurusu)" /><published>2019-02-17T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-02-17T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/17/ingiltere-vizesi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/17/ingiltere-vizesi.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/erasmus-staji-ingiltere/trafalgar.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;trafalgar square&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt; yazında &lt;strong&gt;Erasmus+ Mobility&lt;/strong&gt; kapsamında (namı değer &lt;strong&gt;Erasmus stajı&lt;/strong&gt;) Imperial
College London’da staj yapmıştım. Vize alma süreci gerçekten yorucu ve 
stresliydi. İnternetteki bilgilerin çoğu güncel değildi ve birçoğu birbiri ile 
çelişiyordu. Bu sebeple bu şekilde bir yazı yazıp sizlere yol göstermek 
istiyorum. Vize süreci her şekilde gerçekten sancılı bir süreç ama her şey 
bitip de oraya gittiğinizde çektiğiniz bütün çileyi unutacaksınız.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Öncelikle staj yapacağınız yerden kabul mektubu alma kısmını çoktan tamamlandığınızı varsayıyorum. Ayrıca okulunuzdaki Erasmus stajı hibesinden yararlanmak için gereken işlemleri yaptığınızı ve hibe almaya da hak kazandığınızı farz ederek bu yazıyı yazıyorum. Bu kısımlar için daha sonra detaylı bir yazı yazacağım.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sizin Erasmus stajı kapsamında almanız gereken vize Tier 5 (Temporary Workers) VISA olarak geçiyor. Bu vizenin de birkaç alt türü var ama sizin alacağınız &lt;strong&gt;TIER 5 TW (GOVERNMENT AUTHORISED EXCHANGE)&lt;/strong&gt; vizesi olacak. Bu vizeyi diğer vizelerden farklı kılan ve işi zorlaştıran kısım tam olarak burada devreye giriyor. Bu vize &lt;strong&gt;CoS (Certificate of Sponsorship) Number&lt;/strong&gt; denen bir numara istiyor. CoS Number, İngiltere devletinin sizin staj yapacağınız alan ile aldığınız eğitimin uyuşup uyuşmadığını kontrol etmesine yarayan bir prosedürün parçası diyebilirim. Bu numara olmadan Tier 5 vizesi almanız maalesef mümkün değil. Peki bu numarayı almak için ne yapmamız gerekiyor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cos-number-alma-süreci&quot;&gt;CoS Number Alma Süreci&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CoS Number, British Council’e gerekli belgelerin gönderilmesinin ardından alınabiliyor. Bu konuda hangi evrakların lazım olduğunu falan içeren bir maili size okulunuzun Erasmus koordinatörlüğü gönderiyor. Biz gene işimizi garantiye almak adına bu belgeleri buraya da yazalım.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;* Pasaportunuzun tüm sayfalarının taratılmış hali (boş sayfalar dahil!)
* Erasmus Ofisinden alacağınız hibe yazısı (grant letter)
* Learning Agreement for Traineeship (Before the mobility)
* Kabul mektubu (learning agreement)
* CoS Bilgi Formu (Information for Tier-5 COS Form) (Özenli bir şekilde 
doldurmanızı tavsiye ediyorum.)
* Sabıka Kaydı (Criminal Record)
* Öğrenci Belgesi (Student Certificate)
* Transcript 
* Tier 5 COS Application Form (Erasmus Plus sitesinden indirilecek)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tier 5 hakkında detaylı açıklamayı &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.erasmusplus.org.uk/tier-5-visa-how-to-apply-for-a-certificate-of-sponsorship&quot;&gt;Erasmus Plus sitesindeki Tier 5 bölümünden&lt;/a&gt; öğrenebilirsiniz. Yukarıda bahsedilen Tier 5 CoS Application Form’u da yine bu siteden indireceksiniz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tüm bahsedilen bu belgeleri tek bir .pdf haline getirip okulunuzun Erasmus ofisine gönderin. Erasmus ofisindeki danışmanınız sizin yerinize gerekli maili bu belgelerle birlikte British Council’e gönderecektir. Farklı okuldaki arkadaşlarımdan duyduğuma göre bazı okullarda bu maili sizin göndermeniz bekleniyormuş. Okulunuza hangisi uygunsa ona göre hareket edebilirsiniz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CoS için gerekli belgeleri doldururken dikkat etmeniz gereken bazı önemli noktalar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;* Acceptance letter from host organisation should be stamped. If organization 
doesn't use stamp, it should be notified officially.
* If any additional allowance is indicated on the application form, they are 
required to be listed on the application for as well.
* Erasmus LA for Traineeship should be filled fully and comprehensively. 
* &quot; Is the work placement supernumerary?&quot; question at the 5th page of the 
application form has to be answered as &quot;YES&quot;
* Kabul mektubunuzda Student Job Title/Job Title sizin staj yapacağınız yer 
tarafından yazılmalıdır. CoS formlarındaki Student Job Title/Job Type kısımları 
da kabul mektubuna uygun olarak doldurulmalıdır.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CoS Number alma süreci zaman alan bir süreç ve yoğunluğa göre 6 haftaya kadar vakit alabilir. Bu sebeple elinizi çabuk tutup bir an önce gerekli evrakları hazırlayıp numaranızı alın. Ben hibe sonuçları açıklanmadan önce çoğu evrağı hazırladığım için Mart ayında Cos Number’a başvurmuştum ve 2 gün sonra numaram gelmişti. Ben erken davrandığım için bu kadar hızlı geldiğini düşünüyorum zira o zaman danışmanım bile şaşırmıştı nasıl bu kadar hızlı geldiğine. Siz gene de son ana bırakmayın çünkü Nisan-Haziran ayları arası British Council’in en yoğun olduğu zamanlar. Yukarıda bahsettiğim belgelerin bazılarının fotoğrafını aşağıda görebilirsiniz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learning Agreement for Traineeship (Before the Mobility):
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/erasmus-staji-ingiltere/learning_agreement.png&quot; alt=&quot;LA before&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;CoS Bilgi Formu:
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/erasmus-staji-ingiltere/CoS_Info_Form.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoS Bilgi Formu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tier 5 CoS Application Form (Erasmus Plus sitesinden indirilen):
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/erasmus-staji-ingiltere/Tier5_CoS_Application_Form.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tier5 CoS Application Form&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cos-numberı-kullanarak-tier-5-vizesi-alma-süreci&quot;&gt;CoS Number’ı Kullanarak Tier 5 Vizesi Alma Süreci&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CoS Number başvurusunu halletiğimize göre artık asıl vize başvurusuna geçebiliriz. Asıl vize başvuruları &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visa4uk.fco.gov.uk/&quot;&gt;Visa4UK&lt;/a&gt; üzerinden yapılıyor. Sitede bir sürü doldurmanız gereken yer var o yüzden tavsiyem CoS number’ı beklerken siteye kaydolup vize başvurusuna başlamanız. CoS Number’ınız gelince onu da ekleyip başvurunuzu tamamlamanız.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;British Council size CoS Number’ı gönderdiği mailinde en güncel Tier 5 başvuru rehberinin de pdf halini ek olarak gönderiyor. Bu rehberde &lt;strong&gt;Visa4UK&lt;/strong&gt;‘den nasıl başvuru yapacağınız detaylı bir şekilde anlatılıyor. Size daha CoS Number gelmediğini düşünerek, &lt;a href=&quot;/static/erasmus-staj-ingiltere/Tier5OnlineGuide.pdf&quot;&gt;bana gelen rehberin pdf hali&lt;/a&gt;‘ni paylaşıyorum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visa4UK&lt;/strong&gt;‘e kaydolup bu rehberi de takip ederek VAF9 formunu düzgünce doldurun. Vize başvurusu için gereken belgeler:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;* Pasaportunuz ve fotokopisi
* Varsa eski pasaportlarınız
* TC Kimlik ve fotokopisi
* Öğrenci Belgeniz
* Transkript
* Acceptance Letter
* Learning Agreement Before the Mobility
* Tier 5 CoS Application Formu
* Hibe Yazısı (Grant Letter)
* VAF9 Formu (Visa4UK'de doldurduğumuz)
* CoS Number Maintenance Letter (CoS Başvurusu yaptıktan sonra British 
Council'in size gönderdiği ve üstünde size özel CoS numaranızın yazdığı belge)
* Seyahat ve sağlık sigortanız (Erasmus için kaza, mesuliyet ve sağlık  
sigortalarının hepsi bir arada isteniyor. Bankalarda yapılan sigortalar 
genelde geçerli olmuyor. O yüzden sigorta acentalarından yaptırın ve 
kesinlikle kaza, mesuliyet ve sağlık sigortalarının hepsini yapıyorlar mı 
diye sorun!)
* Ailenizin ya(da) sizin gelirle ilgili tüm belgeleriniz (maaş bordrosu, 
tapu, ruhsat, banka hesap dökümleri vs)
* Ailenizin size sponsor olacağına dair imzalı bir dilekçe
* Sizin geri döneceğinizi bildirdiğiniz dilekçe
(Bu iki dilekçe için taslakları aşağıdaki kısımdan indirebilirsiniz.)
* Uçak Biletleri
* Staj boyunca kalacağınız yeri gösteren bir belge
* Vize randevunuzun **barkodlu** onay belgesi (appointment confirmation)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dilekçe Taslakları:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/static/erasmus-staj-ingiltere/sponsor_dilekce.docx&quot;&gt;Sponsor için dilekçe taslağı&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/static/erasmus-staj-ingiltere/kendi_dilekceniz.doc&quot;&gt;Kendi dilekçenizin taslağı&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOT:&lt;/strong&gt; Uçak biletleri ve kalacak yer konusunda karar birazcık size kalmış. Bazı insanlar ikisini de sadece geçici rezervasyon yaptırıp o şekilde başvuruyor. Bazıları kalacak yer göstermeden başvuruyor. İki şekilde de yapıp vize alan arkadaşlarım oldu. Ben garantici davranıp ikisini de göstermiştim. Belgelerinize güveniyorsanız ikisini de ayarlamanın ekonomik olarak tabii ki bir avantajı oluyor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visa4UK&lt;/strong&gt;‘de başvurunuzu tamamladıktan sonra aracı kurum olan &lt;a href=&quot;https://uk.tlscontact.com/&quot;&gt;TLScontact&lt;/a&gt;‘ın sitesine girip üye olmayı unutmayın. Vize görüşmesine hangi şehirde gidecekseniz o şehirdeki &lt;strong&gt;TLScontact&lt;/strong&gt;‘ın websitesine kaydolun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOT:&lt;/strong&gt; Bütün belgelerinizin ekstra fotokopisini falan alıp kendinizi hiç yormayın. Vize görüşmesinde belgelerinizi taratıp size geri veriyorlar. Dolayısıyla belgelerinizin ıslak imzalı olmasına da gerek yok. Renkli yazdırdığınız sürece bir problem olacağını sanmıyorum. Boşu boşuna ıslak imzalı belgeler için posta ile uğraşmayın.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Umarım atladığım bir yer yoktur. Referans vermesi açısından benim vizem yaklaşık 10 günde çıkmıştı ama duruma göre bu süre 3-4 haftayı da bulabiliyormuş.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Herhangi bir sorunuz olursa yorum kısmından sorabilirsiniz. Bu arada ben herhangi bir danışmanlık şirketine falan gitmedim. Kendim internetten araştırıp hallettim. Size de tavsiyem aynı şekilde yapmanız. &lt;strong&gt;Boş yere vize danışmanlık şirketlerine para vermeyin. Tüm bilgiler internette mevcut! O parayla isterseniz İngiltere dönüşünde bana ufak bir hediye alabilirsiniz :))&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tier 5 ile ilgili ekstra bilgi için &lt;a href=&quot;/static/erasmus-staj-ingiltere/20160816 Annex E Participant Tier 5 Guidelines and Sponsorship Duties.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gov.uk&lt;/strong&gt;‘in yayınladığı dosyalara bakabilirsiniz.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bol şans diliyorum :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/erasmus-staji-ingiltere/potion_room_hp.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;HP Potions Room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/erasmus-staji-ingiltere/trafalgar.JPG" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Create Your Own Blog with Github Pages and Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/01/github-pages-tutorial.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Create Your Own Blog with Github Pages and Jekyll" /><published>2019-02-01T11:49:13+03:00</published><updated>2019-02-01T11:49:13+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/01/github-pages-tutorial</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/01/github-pages-tutorial.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/github-pages-tutorial/github-pages-cover.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Github Pages Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I will try to explain all the necessary steps to create your 
own blog using github pages and Jekyll. I will assume that you have already 
known git and how to use it. If you don’t, you do not need to worry at all.
There are many tutorials to learn github like &lt;a href=&quot;https://guides.github.com/activities/hello-world/&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-setting-up-the-blog&quot;&gt;1-)SETTING UP THE BLOG&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Step:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you need is to create a github repository for your blog and
match it with your local files. In order to do this, follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;github pages
tutorial&lt;/a&gt;. It explains how to setup your own website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second Step:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far we managed to create our own website on github, but whatabout Jekyll?
What is it? Jekyll is some kind of a system that allows you to create nice HTML
webpages without any need to write ugly HTML codes. Instead, it converts your 
writings which are in markdown format (don’t worry it is super easy) to HTML
webpage format. Sounds nice, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until here you should be able to see your website https://username.github.io/
Now it is time to install jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First install ruby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu 16.04 or 18.04:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt-get install ruby-dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu 14.04:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt-get install rubygems-integration
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu 12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt-get install rubygems
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install jekyll using rubygem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo gem install jekyll
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go your website directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd username.github.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It needs to be empty so delete everything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo rm -rf * 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now create new jekyll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ jekyll new .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any problem about bundler in this step install bundler as well&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo gem install bundler
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run ls to check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ ls
config.yaml _posts about.md ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thanks to jekyll we can view our website locally without committing to 
github. This allows to easily check changes we have made before commits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ jekyll serve
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command will publish your website locally. Look for the line&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Server address: http://127.0.0.1:4000/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see what your website will look like by visiting this local adress in 
your web browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third Step&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are happy with the look of your website, you need to publish all the 
changes to github to make it available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://username.github.io/&quot;&gt;https://username.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git add *
$ git commit -m &quot;Website is online&quot;
$ git push origin master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you and everybody else can see your website at https://username.github.io&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-customize-your-blog&quot;&gt;2-)CUSTOMIZE YOUR BLOG&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Comment Section Into Your Blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to allow readers to comment on your posts, you can use very common
service named &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/home&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;. Sign up and do not forget 
your Disqus username (your website short-name). For me, it is https-samialperen-
github-io as it can be seen in below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/github-pages-tutorial/disqus_short_name.png&quot; alt=&quot;disqus_short_name&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to your website git repository directory and open _config.yaml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd username.github.io
$ gedit _config.yaml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you use jekyll new to create your website, it uses jekyll minima theme 
by default and it is quite easy to add comment section to this theme. If you are
using different theme, then the procedure might be different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of _config.yaml file add this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;disqus:
    shortname: your_disqus_website_shortname
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change your_disqus_website_shortname to yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, do not forget to add your website url in _config.yaml file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;url: &quot;https://username.github.io&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example _config.yaml:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;title: Your awesome title
email: your-email@example.com
description: &amp;gt;- # this means to ignore newlines until &quot;baseurl:&quot;
  Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this
  line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for
  Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
baseurl: &quot;&quot; # the subpath of your site, e.g. /blog
url: &quot;https://samialperen.github.io&quot;
twitter_username: jekyllrb
github_username:  jekyll

# Build settings
markdown: kramdown
theme: minima
#plugins:
#  - jekyll-feed
disqus:
    shortname: https-samialperen-github-io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commit and push your changes into github and you can see comment section at the
end of your posts like below:
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/github-pages-tutorial/comment_section.png&quot; alt=&quot;comment_section&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write New Blog Posts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you will understand power of markdowns and jekyll better. To write new blog 
posts create a markdown file under username.github.io/_posts directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd username.github.io/_posts
$ touch 2019-02-01-github-pages-tutorial.markdown
$ gedit 2019-02-01-github-pages-tutorial.markdown
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write your blog post as you wish regarding markdown syntax. The only thing
you need to be careful is markdown file name. It should obey the following
format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-post-name.markdown
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, at the beginning of the markdown file you need to write a few lines&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
layout: post
title:  &quot;Post Title&quot;
date:   Post-Date    #should be same with filename
---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example markdown file of jekyll:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
layout: post
title:  &quot;Welcome to Jekyll!&quot;
date:   2019-01-31 16:20:13 +0300
categories: jekyll update
---
You’ll find this post in your `_posts` directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run `jekyll serve`, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.

To add new posts, simply add a file in the `_posts` directory that follows the convention `YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext` and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.

Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:


&amp;lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;&amp;lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&amp;gt;def&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&amp;gt;print_hi&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&amp;gt;(&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&amp;gt;name&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&amp;gt;)&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&amp;gt;puts&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&amp;gt;&quot;Hi, &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&amp;gt;#{&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&amp;gt;name&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&amp;gt;}&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&amp;gt;&quot;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&amp;gt;end&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&amp;gt;print_hi&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&amp;gt;(&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&amp;gt;'Tom'&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&amp;gt;)&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&amp;gt;#=&amp;amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/pre&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;


Check out the [Jekyll docs][jekyll-docs] for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at [Jekyll’s GitHub repo][jekyll-gh]. If you have questions, you can ask them on [Jekyll Talk][jekyll-talk].

[jekyll-docs]: https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home
[jekyll-gh]:   https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll
[jekyll-talk]: https://talk.jekyllrb.com/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have difficulties with markdown file syntax, you can follow 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.markdowntutorial.com/&quot;&gt;markdown_tutorials&lt;/a&gt;. It is super easy to 
learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Google Analytics to Your Blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to analyze your visitors and get more information about page views,
you can add Google Analytics to your blog. Please see step 7 of &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancaffey.github.io/2016/03/17/jekyll-tutorial.html&quot;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for this tutorial. I hope it helps for anybody who wants to create
his/her own blog without having too much trouble. The best thing about github
pages is that it is totally free. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/github-pages-tutorial/github-pages-cover.jpeg" /></entry></feed>